本字幕由志愿者义务贡献，采用许可协议
知识共享 署名-非商业性使用-相同方式共享 3.0 美国
>> Welcome to Stanford CS193P,
欢迎参加 2017 年冬季学期斯坦福
Developing Applications for iOS, winter of 2017.
CS193P 课程，iOS 应用程序开发
CS193P课程,iOS应用程序开发
This is lecture number five?
这是第五讲吗?
Is that right? The lecture number five?
是这样吗?5号的讲座吗?
Yeah, lecture number five.
是的,讲座是5号。
Today we are going to start off with a little demo,
今天我们先来做一个小演示，
where I'm gonna take the application we worked on last
我要把我们最后工作的应用程序放在哪里
time, and add a model to it.
时间，并为它添加一个模型。
Cuz we have only worked on the view part of that,
因为我们只研究了其中的一部分，
building that nice cool FaceView,
建立一个很酷的FaceView，
now we are going to add a model to that MVC.
现在我们要向这个MVC添加一个模型。
Then we're going to come back to the slides and
然后我们会回到幻灯片
I'm going to do some slides on gestures.
我要做一些关于手势的幻灯片。
Obviously, you want to be able to have input to your app,
很明显，你想要能够输入你的应用程序，
you need to know how to do multi-touch gestures,
你需要知道如何做多点触控手势，
we'll talk all about that, and
我们会谈到这一点
then I will go back to our FaceView application and
然后回到FaceView应用程序
we will add some gestures, pinching, panning, tapping.
我们会添加一些手势，捏，拍，敲。
And finally, I will go back to the slides again and
最后，我会再次回到幻灯片
start talking about multiple MVCs.
开始谈论多个mvc。
How to build bigger applications that are made out
如何构建更大的应用程序
of combining MVCs, so that's what's on tap for today.
把mvc结合起来，这就是今天要讲的内容。
So let's jump right back into this FaceIt Demo.
让我们回到这个FaceIt Demo中。
And if you remember where we left off,
如果你们还记得我们讲到哪了，
we had this nice view, it was really cool because,
我们有一个很好的视图，它很酷，因为，
in Interface Builder, we could do things like open the eyes.
在接口构建器中，我们可以像打开眼睛那样做。
We could make it really big,
我们可以把它变得很大，
we could make it really small, or anywhere in between.
我们可以让它很小，或者介于两者之间。
And we could change the color, green,
我们可以改变颜色，绿色，
something like that, so that's cool.
像这样，很酷。
And this is a nice reusable thing that's got a little
这是一个很好的可重复使用的东西
public API to it.
公共API。
These inspectable things are all public,
这些检查表都是公开的，
so, we can set the mouth curvature, we can open and
所以，我们可以设定嘴的弯曲度，我们可以打开
close the eyes, we can change those things, like scale.
闭上眼睛，我们可以改变这些东西，比如音阶。
And so, it's nice, it's this nice reusable face.
很好，这是一张很好的可重复使用的脸。
And what we're going to do is make our MVC have a model.
我们要做的是让MVC有一个模型。
That model is not gonna match up exactly to what our
这个模型不符合我们的
FaceView can do, because that's the way models work.
FaceView可以这样做，因为这是模型工作的方式。
Models in the world are often databases or something, their
世界上的模型通常是数据库或其他东西
schema doesn't quite match what view you have around.
模式与你周围的视图不完全相符。
So you, the job of the controller is to interpret
所以你，控制器的工作就是解释
that model for the view as best it can.
这种模式是最好的。
And interpret input from the view also to affect the model.
并从视图中解释输入也会影响模型。
So let's go back to our controller,
我们回到控制器，
you can see that we have no model, we also have no outlets
你可以看到我们没有模型，也没有outlet
to our view here, so, let's add both of those things.
在这里，我们把这两个都加起来。
I'm gonna start by adding an outlet to our FaceView, so
首先我要在FaceView中添加一个outlet
remember how we do that, we got our storyboard on screen.
记住我们是怎么做的，我们在屏幕上得到了故事板。
I'm gonna get them both on screen at the same time and
我将同时在屏幕上同时播放它们
then I'm gonna control drag.
然后control拖动。
And I'm control dragging from my FaceView to create
我从FaceView中control拖动创建
an outlet to it,
一个出口,
in exactly the same way I would control drag to a label,
同样的，我将拖动到标签上，
or button, or anything else, so
或者按钮，或者其他任何东西
nothing special about the FaceView.
FaceView没有什么特别之处。
So I'm just gonna hold down control and drag in here,
按住control，拖动到这里，
and I'm gonna create an outlet,
我要创建一个outlet，
I'll call this outlet my FaceView.
我将它命名为my FaceView。
That's a perfectly good name for it.
这是一个很好的名字。
Hit connect and there we go, we get this code that you're
点击连接，我们就会得到这个代码
quite used to here, which is this IBOutlet weak var.
很习惯这里，这是IBOutlet弱var。
Now we have a connection to our view, and remember, in MVC
现在我们有了一个连接到我们的视图，记住，在MVC
picture, the controller can have green arrows to its view,
图像，控制器可以有绿色箭头的视图，
that's this, and it can have green arrows to its model.
就是这样，它可以有绿色的箭头。
So let's create a connection to the model.
让我们创建一个到模型的连接。
So what is gonna be our model of our MVC?
那么我们的MVC模型是什么呢?
I'm actually going to drag that in, right here,
我要把它拖进来，在这里，
it's called facial expression.
它被称为面部表情。
When you drag things in I strongly recommend
当你拖东西的时候，我强力推荐
you have this Destination, Copy items if needed,
您有这个目的地，如果需要，复制项目，
otherwise, when you drag in a class, or structure, or
否则，当您拖进一个类，或结构，或
something, you'll be pointing to it.
你会指着它。
So if you change it in, wherever you got it from,
所以如果你改变它，不管你从哪里得到它，
it will be changing it in your project,
它会在你的项目中改变它，
so, it's usually what we wanna do.
所以，这通常是我们想要做的。
Maybe that might be what you want,
也许这就是你想要的，
in certain circumstances, but usually wanna copy it in.
在某些情况下，但通常是想把它复制进去。
So let's take a look at this thing that I brought in,
让我们来看看我带来的东西，
it's a struct and it's gonna be the model of our FaceView.
它是一个struct，它将是FaceView的模型。
And it's a really simple FacialExpression,
这是一个非常简单的面部表情，
that's what this represents, this struct.
这就是这个结构。
And it has positions of the eyes,
它有眼睛的位置，
open eyes, closed eyes, squinting eyes, unfortunately,
睁开眼睛，闭着眼睛，眯着眼睛，不幸的是，
we can't represent that in our view but it's in the model,
我们不能在视图中表示它但它在模型中，
we'll have to figure out the best we can do.
我们得想出最好的办法。
It's also got a mouth, and the mouth can frown or smirk, or
它也有张嘴，嘴巴可以皱眉或傻笑，或者
it can grin, or smile,
它可以微笑，也可以微笑，
notice there's nothing in this model about mouth curvature.
注意，这个模型中没有任何关于嘴曲率的东西。
It doesn't know anything about mouth curvature,
它不知道任何关于嘴曲率的东西，
it just knows about grins and
它只知道grins和
frowns, things like that, that's what the model is.
皱眉，诸如此类，这就是模型。
It's also kinda cool, it knows how to give you a happier
它也很酷，它知道如何让你更快乐
version of itself, or a sadder version of itself.
版本的本身，或者是它自己的悲伤版本。
That's what these bars do,
这就是这些条的作用，
they just wanna return a happier or sadder.
他们只是想让自己更快乐更难过。
But primarily, this struct is just an expression to keep
但首先，这个结构只是一个表达
track of the state of the eyes and the mouth.
观察眼睛和嘴巴的状态。
So I'm going to, in my controller,
在控制器中，
create a green arrow to it, or a var for it.
创建一个绿色的箭头，或者一个var。
We're gonna call it Expression,
我们叫它表达式，
cuz it's a facial expression.
因为这是一个面部表情。
And it's type FacialExpression,
FacialExpression类型,
and actually,
实际上,
let's have a starting facial expression have eyes,
让我们来做一个面部表情，
which are, let's say, open, and a mouth, which is a grin.
也就是说，打开一个嘴巴，一个咧嘴笑。
That sound like a happy place to start.
这听起来像是一个很好的开始。
So that's great,
这是伟大的,
now, remember that the primary job of a controller
现在，请记住，控制器的主要工作
is to interpret the model for the view and vice versa.
是为视图解释模型，反之亦然。
So I'm gonna add a private function here-
我要在这里添加一个私有函数
you'll all often have a method or
你会经常有一个方法
a number of methods in your controller like this.
你的控制器中有很多这样的方法。
This one I'm gonna call updateUI.
这个我要调用updateUI。
And the job of this method is just to
这个方法的工作就是
make the model match the UI, tha's i's job.
让模型匹配UI，这是我的工作。
Tha's what this method is gonna do.
这就是这个方法的作用。
So, what do we have to do to make our model,
我们要做什么来做模型，
this facial expression, match our UI?
这个表情，匹配我们的UI ?
Well, we have to deal with the eyes and
我们必须处理好眼睛
we have to deal with the mouth.
我们必须处理好嘴巴。
So, let's deal with the eyes first, that's pretty easy, so,
我们先来处理一下眼睛，这很简单，
I'm just going to switch on my expressions.eyes.
我只是想转换一下我的表现。
And in the case that the eyes are open in the model,
在这种情况下，眼睛是在模型中打开的，
then it's easy, I can just take my faceView and
这很简单，我可以用faceView
set it's eyesOpen to true, that's obvious how we do that.
把它看得很清楚，很明显我们就是这么做的。
And this face, you remember, is this outlet,
这张脸，你记得，是这个出口，
that I just created there, and so, that's obvious.
我刚在那里创建的，很明显。
How about the case where the eyes are closed in the model?
在模型中闭上眼睛的情况如何?
Well, that's the faceView.eyesOpen,
嗯,这是faceView.eyesOpen,
are gonna be false.
会是假的。
And finally, there's this case in the model
最后，在模型中有这个例子
where we're squinting, and here,
在这里，
I don't really have a way to represent that.
我没有一个方法来表示它。
So I'm just going to say that in that case our eyes
我想说的是，在这种情况下我们的眼睛
are gonna be closed because, squinting is more like having
会关闭吗，眯眼更像有
your eyes closed than having them open.
你的眼睛闭上了，没有睁开。
But we don't always have exactly the view we want to
但我们并不总是有我们想要的观点
represent our model, so we're doing the best we can here.
代表我们的模型，所以我们在这里做的最好。
So that is the eyes, pretty straightforward.
这就是眼睛，很简单。
Now the mouth, I could do the same thing for
现在，我可以做同样的事情
the mouth here, case expression.mouth,
这里的嘴，用例表示，
if it's a grin, set the mouth curvature to this.
如果是咧着嘴笑，那就把嘴弯成这样。
If it's normal, set the mouth curvature to that,
如果是正常的，把嘴的曲率设为，
but that code is kind of messy,
但这个代码有点乱，
(make some space here so it's up higher), what if
I created a little private var here, actually make it a let.
我在这里创建了一个私有var，让它变成一个。
And I'm gonna call it mouthCurvatures, and
我把它叫做口曲率
it's gonna be a dictionary, and in the dictionary,
它将是一本字典，在字典里，
the values are gonna be FacialExpression.MouthPositi-
值会FacialExpression.MouthPositi -
ons, maybe a grin.
国家统计局,也许一个笑容。
And the value is gonna be a mouth curvature, so
它的值是一个口曲率
what's a good thing for a grin?
笑什么好呢?
I think I decided 0.5.
我想我确定了0。5。
So this is just gonna be a dictionary with
所以这就是一本字典
mouth position in the model, mouthCurvatures for the view.
在模型的口位置，视图的口曲率。
So I'm just creating this little mapping data structure.
我在创建这个小的映射数据结构。
So let's do this for all, let's map this.
我们来做一下，把它映射出来。
For all of our facial expressions right here.
对于所有的面部表情。
Notice, by the way,
注意,顺便说一下,
that Swift was able to infer the type of this dictionary.
那个斯威夫特能够推断出这本字典的类型。
Cuz it only has one item in it, and the types of those two
因为它只有一个项，和那两个的类型
things are obvious from what they are.
事情是显而易见的。
So now that it knows that, by the way,
现在它知道了，顺便说一下，
we can be a little more succinct and just say like,
我们可以更简洁一些，比如，
frown is -1.0 and smile is 1.0.
皱眉是- 1.0，微笑是1.0。
And obviously neutral would be 0.0.
显然中性是0。0。
Did I get them all?
我都买了吗?
Smirk, how about smirk?
得意的笑,得意的笑呢?
Nope, that smirk we'll say is -0.5.
不，那个smirk我们会说- 0。5。
So I've just put those mouth curvatures in this nice
所以我刚刚把这些嘴弯曲了
little table.
小表。
And so now in my update UI,
在更新UI中，
I'm just gonna set my faceView's mouthCurvature
我要设置我的faceView的口曲率
equal to looking up in the mouthCurvatures,
就等于向上看，
the model's mouth.
模型的嘴。
I just kinda wanna do it this way to kinda show you that you
我只是想用这个方法来展示给你们看
don't always have to forcefully case every single
不要总是对每一个人都有强有力的理由
thing when you have an enum.
当你有一个enum的时候。
Sometimes you can use things like this.
有时你可以用这样的东西。
Now, I have an error there,
现在，我有一个错误，
anybody know why I have an error?
有人知道我为什么出错吗?
Can anyone guess?
谁能猜猜吗?
Optional, yeah.
可选的,是的。
Alright, people are getting the optional thing.
好吧，人们正在得到可选的东西。
Good. MouthCurvature,
好。MouthCurvature,
what type is that?
什么类型呢?
That is a double, and mouthCurvature sub
这是一个双头，和口曲率
expression.mouth, what type is that?
表达式。嘴，那是什么类型的?
It's an optional double.
这是一个可选的两倍。
And that's because this expression might not be
这是因为这个表达式可能不是
in that dictionary.
那本字典。
So I'm gonna use that defaulting thing we learned
我将使用我们学过的默认值
and say, if I can't find the expression mouth,
如果我找不到表达的嘴，
we are gonna have neutral mouth, not smiling or
我们的嘴是中性的，不是微笑的
frowning as our curvature.
皱着眉头曲率。
Now, we have this great update UI.
现在，我们有了这个很棒的更新UI。
When should we call this thing?
我们应该什么时候给它打电话?
Well, we certainly need to call this thing anytime our
嗯，我们当然需要在任何时候给它打电话
model changes.
模型的变化。
If our model changes to have a different expression,
如果我们的模型改变成一个不同的表达式，
we gotta update our UI.
我们必须更新我们的UI。
So how are we gonna do that?
我们要怎么做呢?
We're gonna use this cool feature that I talked about
我们要用这个很酷的功能
last time called property observers, this didSet thing.
上次叫财产观察者的是，这个didSet。
So didSet allows you on any of your vars,
所以didSet允许你在任何一个vars上，
if it changes, you can execute some code.
如果它发生变化，您可以执行一些代码。
So anytime someone sets this expression,
每当有人设置这个表达式时，
I'm just going to update my UI.
我要更新我的UI。
Now, there's one other place that I wanna
现在，还有一个我想要的地方
update my UI though, it's a little less obvious, and
更新我的UI，这有点不太明显
that is with this property observer.
这就是这个属性观察者。
What am I doing here?
我在这里做什么?
This property is the outlet,
这个属性是outlet，
that thing I Ctrl+dragged to my faceView.
我Ctrl +拖动到faceView。
And when we first start up, it's not set.
当我们第一次开始的时候，它不是固定的。
iOS takes a few microseconds to actually connect this up.
iOS只需要几微秒就能将其连接起来。
That's why this is an optional, remember?
这就是为什么这是可选的，记得吗?
In that short amount of time, what if the model gets set.
在这么短的时间内，如果模型被设置好了。
Then update UI is not gonna work because the faceView
更新UI不会起作用，因为faceView
hasn't been connected yet.
尚未连接。
So that's no good.
这是没有好。
Also we initialized our FacialExpression to be this.
还初始化了FacialExpression。
When you initialize something, didSet does not get called.
当你初始化一些东西时，didSet不会被调用。
didSet is only called if someone externally sets
didSet只有在外部设置时才调用
the expression.
表达式。
The initial thing does not cause it to be set.
初始的东西不会导致它被设置。
So when is didSet gonna happen?
什么时候会发生?
It's gonna happen only once when iOS hooks up this outlet
只有当iOS连接到这个outlet时才会发生
to that faceView, then this didSet is gonna get called.
对于这个faceView，这个didSet会被调用。
That's the only time it's ever gonna get called.
这是它唯一一次被调用。
But at that time, we're gonna update our UI.
但在那个时候，我们要更新UI。
Now, there's one other minor thing here.
现在，这里还有一个小问题。
What if this gets called before this happens?
如果这在发生之前被调用了怎么办?
This is gonna crash our program
这会让我们的程序崩溃
because until this gets hooked up to iOS, this is nil.
因为在这个连接到iOS之前，这是nil。
The only reason we don't have to say exclamation point here
我们不需要在这里写感叹号的唯一原因
is cuz we have this implicitly unwrapped optional here, but
因为我们在这里有一个隐式打开的选项，但是
it is an optional.
这是一个可选的。
So how can we deal with that?
那么我们该如何应对呢?
We don't want update UI to crash our program
我们不需要更新UI来破坏我们的程序
if the expression should happen to be set before that
如果表达式应该在此之前设置
thing gets wired up.
件事被连接起来。
Now that thing gets wired up pretty soon, so
现在这个东西很快就被连接起来了
probably not likely to happen, but it could.
可能不太可能发生，但它可以。
So, we're gonna do that by using this chaining,
我们要用这个链接来做这个，
this optional chaining.
这个可选的链接。
Remember the optional chaining,
记得可选的链接,
where you can put a question mark there.
你可以在那里放一个问号。
And if the thing that you put the question mark on evaluates
如果你把问号放在计算值上
to nil, the rest of that line of code is just ignored.
对于nil，这一行代码的其余部分都被忽略了。
Perfect, faceView?.eyesOpen, if faceView's not set,
完美,faceView ?。eyesOpen，如果faceView没有设置，
we'll just ignore that.
我们会忽略这一点。
We're not gonna set the eyes open to anything,
我们不会让眼睛看到任何东西，
that line is just gonna be aborted immediately.
这一行马上就会被中止。
This is something you often wanna do in your update
这是你经常想在更新中做的事情
UI things is protect against your outlets not being set
UI事物是保护你的outlet不被设置
And it's all gonna be fine, because if this got sent, and
一切都会好起来的，因为如果它被发送了
this has not been, and then this happens, and
这不是，然后这就发生了
none of these lines of code execute, no problem.
这些代码都没有执行，没有问题。
Because when this does get hooked up,
因为当它被连接起来的时候，
this is gonna get called again.
这将再次被调用。
And this time, it'll be able to do it.
这次，它就能做到。
So that it.
所以它。
Let's run our little app here and
让我们在这里运行我们的小程序
see if we get an open eyes grin.
看看我们是不是睁着眼睛笑。
In other words,
换句话说,
let's see if our UI reflects what's in our model.
让我们看看我们的UI是否反映了我们模型中的内容。
And sure enough, open eyes and a little grin.
果然，睁开眼睛，露出一丝笑容。
Let's try closed
让我们尝试关闭
eyes, closed and
眼睛,关闭,
a little frown.
有点皱眉。
Bingo!
宾果!
So now we have done what we need to do in our controller,
现在我们已经做了我们需要在控制器中做的事情，
which is we're interpreting our model for our view.
这就是我们对视图的解释。
And anytime we set the model from now on,
当我们从现在开始建立模型时，
it's gonna update our view automatically.
它会自动更新我们的视图。
So the question is, what if I forgot to put this little
问题是，如果我忘了写这个
question mark right here?
问号呢?
Probably everything would be fine because you don't set
可能一切都会很好，因为你没有设置
your model before that Outlook gets wired up by iOS cuz it
在此之前，你的模型被iOS系统所连接
wires it up really soon.
很快就把它连接起来。
But if you did,
但如果你做了,
And so that's how you would know,
这就是你要知道的，
"oops", you messed that up.
And sometimes you'll forget to put that question mark there,
有时你会忘记把这个问号放在那里，
You do all your coding and you never call that model earlier.
你做了所有的编码，你从来没有提前调用那个模型。
it's fine.
它很好。
But then later, you change your code in a way that
但之后，你会以一种方式改变你的代码
does accept the model before that thing, and boom.
在此之前接受模型，然后繁荣。
It crashes, and you find it right away.
它崩溃了，你马上就能找到它。
That's why crashing is
这就是为什么崩溃
not always the worst thing in the world.
并不总是世界上最糟糕的事情。
Crashing helps you find bugs like that.
崩溃可以帮助你找到类似的bug。
You just hope you don't ship it out, and
你只希望你不要把它运出去
the customers find that bug for you that way.
客户会通过这种方式找到bug。
So that's it, that's all I wanted to do is show
这就是我想要展示的
you now we have a complete MVC.
现在我们有一个完整的MVC。
It's got a model, it's got a view,
它有一个模型，它有一个视图，
it's got a controller that is interpreting for each other.
它有一个控制器来相互解释。
So we can go back to our slides and
我们可以回到幻灯片
learn about gestures, and
了解手势,和
then we'll add some gestures to this thing.
然后我们再加上一些手势。
So, how do we get those touches?
那么，我们如何得到这些触摸呢?
Now, it is possible to get notified
现在，可以得到通知
of raw touch events like a touch, meaning a finger,
像触摸这样的原始触摸事件，也就是指手指，
went down on the screen, it moved, it went up.
在屏幕上，它移动了，它上升了。
Two fingers went down,
两个手指下降,
you can find out all about that, but we never do.
你可以知道这一切，但我们从来没有。
Too complicated, trying to figure out whether this, down,
太复杂了，想弄清楚，
swipe, up is a swipe versus just moving, that's too hard.
滑动，向上是滑动，而只是移动，这太困难了。
So we're gonna let iOS do that for us.
我们让iOS为我们做这个。
And we call that interacting with multi touch,
我们称其为多点触控，
touch via gestures.
通过手势触摸。
So we're not even gonna learn about about the raw
所以我们甚至不能了解原始的情况
touch input in this course, just gestures.
触摸输入在这门课，只是手势。
So gestures are recognized
所以手势识别
by this class called the UIGestureRecognizer.
通过这个类叫做UIGestureRecognizer。
Actually, not by UIGestureRecognizer itself,
实际上，不是UIGestureRecognizer本身，
that's an abstract class.
这是一个抽象类。
How many people know what an abstract class is?
有多少人知道什么是抽象类?
Raise your hand if you know what that is.
如果你知道那是什么，请举手。
Okay, so I'll take a second to tell ya.
好吧，我花点时间告诉你。
So an abstract class is a class that, it's only
抽象类只是一个类，它只是
purpose in life is to be the super class of other classes.
生活的目的是成为其他阶级的超级阶级。
And you never actually create an abstract class, okay?
实际上你从来没有创建一个抽象类?
You only create subclasses of it,
你只创建了它的子类，
instances of subclasses of it.
它的子类的实例。
So UI gesture recognizer's abstract, you would never
ui手势识别器的抽象，你永远不会
create a UI, you'd never call an initializer on UI gesture
创建一个UI，你不会在UI手势上调用初始化器
recognizer.
识别器。
Instead there's a bunch of subclasses which I'm gonna
相反，我要讲一堆子类
talk about and you would call the initializer on them.
讨论一下，你就会调用初始化器。
Now there's two parts to using a gesture recognizer here.
这里有两个部分使用手势识别器。
One is you have to ask a UIView, please start
一个是你必须要问UIView，请开始
recognizing this gesture, like a swipe or a pan or whatever.
意识到这个手势，就像滑动或平底锅之类的。
And then number two is, when the recognizer does recognize
第二个是，当识别器识别的时候
it, it wants to call you back with a handler,
它想给你回一个处理器，
what we call a handler, a gesture handler.
我们称之为handler，一个手势处理程序。
So there's the recognizer that you add to a view and
这就是你在视图中添加的识别器
then there's the handler, anybody can be the handler,
然后是处理器，任何人都可以是处理器，
as you'll see.
正如您将看到的。
Almost always it's either the view itself or a controller,
通常它要么是视图本身，要么是控制器，
but anybody could be it.
但任何人都可以做到。
Now the adding of the gesture recognizer is done with
现在添加了手势识别器
a method called add gesture recognizer in UIView.
一种在UIView中添加手势识别器的方法。
And that method is usually called by controllers,
这个方法通常由控制器来调用，
why do controllers call that?
为什么控制器调用这个?
That's because a controller wants to control whether
这是因为控制器想要控制
the things in its view recognize certain gestures.
在它的视图中，事物识别某些手势。
They might wanna turn off certain gestures or or
他们可能会想要关闭某些手势或
not turn on certain gestures, so
所以，不要打开某些手势
the controller is often controlling that.
控制器经常控制它。
But occasionally you do get a UIView that will add
但有时候你会得到一个UIView
a gesture to itself, like scroll view.
像滚动视图一样的手势。
Because a scroll view without the pan gesture, or
因为滚动视图没有平移手势，或者
without the pinching gesture if it can zoom,
没有捏捏手势，如果它能变焦，
it's not even a scroll view.
它甚至不是一个滚动视图。
In other words, that gesture is so
换句话说，这个手势是这样的
fundamental to what a scroll view is that scroll view adds
滚动视图的基本原理是滚动视图
It'd, you'd have some API to turn it off, but it adds it to
它会，你会有一些API来关闭它，但它将它添加到
it to itself.
它本身。
itself, it doesn't make some controller add this gesture,
它本身并没有让控制器添加这个手势，
it just recognizes pan and pinch.
它只识别平移和缩放。
So mostly it's done by controllers,
大部分都是由控制器完成的，
though you'll see that.
尽管你会发现。
The second thing, the handler,
第二，处理器，
okay that could either be the controller or the view.
可以是控制器，也可以是视图。
And what it really depends on is whether the gesture affects
它真正依赖的是这个手势是否会影响
the model, or
模型中,或
whether the gesture affects just the view, okay.
这个手势是否影响了视图，好的。
If the gesture only affects the view,
如果这个手势只影响到视图，
then the view will probably handle it.
然后视图可能会处理它。
But if the gesture affects the model directly,
但如果这个手势直接影响模型，
now the controller has to
现在控制器必须
handle it because a view can't see the model.
处理它，因为视图看不到模型。
So the handler is either controller view and not, and
handler是控制器视图，不是
you'll see that in the demo.
你们会在demo中看到。
I'm gonna have one handler that's a model, one and
我将有一个处理器，它是一个模型，一个和
one that controls view and you'll see where we put them.
一个控制视图，你会看到我们把它们放在哪里。
Alright, so what's the code look like to add a gesture
好的，那么代码是怎样添加一个手势的
recognizer to a view?
识别器视图?
So for my example here,
我举个例子，
let's say you had a view, and in this code I'm gonna
假设你有一个视图，在这个代码中，我要
put here by the way is gonna be in a controller.
顺便提一下，这是一个控制器。
Let's say it has one of its views that it wants to add
假设它有一个它想要添加的视图
a pan gesture, a pan gesture is put your finger down on
一个平移手势，一个平移手势，就是把你的手指放在上面
the screen and move around.
屏幕和移动。
That's called panning around in the view.
这就是所谓的平移。
So this is what it looks like, a good place to add a gesture
这就是它看起来的样子，一个添加手势的好地方
recognizer is in the didSet of an outlet for that view.
识别器位于该视图的一个出口的didSet中。
Because that's, as soon as you can get a hold of it anyway,
因为，一旦你能得到它，
your iOS just sets, set that outlet up for you, so
你的iOS只是设置，为你设置outlet，所以
now you've got a hold of that view.
现在你已经掌握了这一观点。
Now you can send a message to that view,
现在你可以发送一条消息到那个视图，
addGestureRecognizer.
addGestureRecognizer。
Here I have this var, this outlet called pannableView,
这里有一个var，这个outlet叫pannableView，
this is the view that I wanna add the pan gesture to.
这是我想要添加平移手势的视图。
And you can see that in its didSet,
你可以看到它的didSet，
in other words when iOS wires this up,
换句话说，当iOS连接起来的时候，
I'm going to do this addGestureRecognizer.
我要做这个addGestureRecognizer。
First I'm gonna create the gesture recognizer,
首先我要创建手势识别器，
notice I'm saying UIPanGestureRecognizer, in it,
注意，我说的是UIPanGestureRecognizer，
in the initializer for that.
在初始化器中。
Not UIGestureRecognizer, I'm creating a concrete
不是UIGestureRecognizer，我在创建一个具体的
gesture recognizer which is for panning.
手势识别器用于平移。
And that it has two arguments, the both of these arguments
它有两个参数，这两个参数
are the handler, how this thing is handled.
是处理器，它是怎么处理的。
The target is who's gonna handle it, and
目标是谁来处理它，和
the action is what method is going to handle it.
方法就是处理它的方法。
So now in the case here, the target,
现在在这里，目标，
I'm having the target will be myself, the view controller.
我的目标是我自己，视图控制器。
This is obviously in the view controller because this is in
这显然在视图控制器中，因为它在
an outlet property observer,
一个出口财产观察者,
that would only make sense in a view controller.
这在视图控制器中是很有意义的。
And so the target is myself, I'm going to set,
所以目标是我自己，我要设置，
ask when this pan gestures starts to be recognized
问一下这个手势什么时候开始被识别
it's gonna be sending me the action here to handle it.
它会发送给我这里的操作来处理它。
And the action, you notice you have to say #selector to
这个动作，你注意到你必须选择# selector
specify the method.
指定的方法。
Don't get confused the difference between a function
不要混淆函数之间的区别
type, a type that is a function and
类型，是一个函数和
an actual method in a class.
一个类中的实际方法。
We use #selector to say this is a method,
我们使用# selector表示这是一个方法，
I wanna call this specific method in my class.
我想在课堂上讲这个具体方法。
And notice I've said ViewController.pan(
注意，我已经说过了viewcontroller . pan(
recognizer:), well that means that the method that's gonna
识别器:)，这意味着这个方法
be called is called pan.
被称为pan。
And it has one argument, whose external name is recognizer:
它有一个参数，它的外部名字是识别器:
that's what that means.
这是什么意思。
The ViewController., means that method is in myself.
ViewController。，方法就是我自己。
If it was in my view it would probably be like
如果在我看来，可能会是这样
PannableView.whatever.
PannableView.whatever。
This could also be self.pan, that's allowed,
这也可以是自我。锅,这是允许的,
saying pan.panGesture, pan recognizer in myself.
说锅。panGesture,pan识别器在我自己。
Also you could omit it, that part in totally and
你也可以省略它，这部分是完全的
just say panRecognizer: because the default is for
只是说pan识别器:因为默认是for
it to be in myself.
它属于我自己。
So there's three ways I could have specified that,
我有三种方法来说明，
viewController.pan, self.pan, or just pan.
viewController。锅、自我。锅,或者只是平底锅。
But notice it does have that argument by the way,
但是注意它确实有这个论证，
that argument is gonna be the recognizer passed back to me.
这个参数就是我返回的识别器。
So when the pan starts to be recognized, it's gonna call
当pan开始被识别时，它会调用
this method, and that recognizer is gonna be passed.
这个方法，那个识别器会被传递。
This pan gesture recognizer called panGestureRecognizer
这个手势识别器被称为panGestureRecognizer
right there, that's gonna be passed back to me each time.
就在那里，每次都会传回给我。
Now I've got a gesture recognizer for
现在我有了一个手势识别器
panning, I just add it to the view,
平移，我把它加到视图上，
only views are capable of recognizing gestures.
只有视图才能识别手势。
So if you have a gesture recognizer,
如果你有一个手势识别器，
the only addGestureRecognizer method in the entire UI kit is
在整个UI工具包中唯一的addGestureRecognizer方法是
in UIView, so you have to send it to UIView, or
在UIView中，你必须把它发送给UIView
a subclass of UIView.
UIView的一个子类。
Let's talk about the handling, so now this is code,
我们来讨论一下处理，这是代码，
adds the handler so
添加处理程序,所以
that the view is gonna start looking for pan gestures.
这个视图将开始寻找平移手势。
And then when it finds them,
当它发现它们的时候，
it's going to start calling this pan recognizer.
它将开始调用这个pan识别器。
Now before we can look at the code for
在我们看代码之前
that we gotta understand a few things about it.
我们必须了解一些事情。
One is that when you get a gesture like a pan or
一种是当你做手势时，像平底锅
a pinch you need some concrete subclass specific information
必要时，您需要一些具体的子类特定信息
about it like a pan.
就像平底锅一样。
You gotta know where it is, or a pinch,
你必须知道它在哪里，或者缩放，
you gotta know much you pinched.
你得知道你掐了多少。
So we have to understand what that means,
所以我们必须明白这意味着什么，
now for a pan gesture recognizer, there are three.
现在，对于一个平移手势识别器，有三个。
It's actually a little more, but there's this three very
实际上还有一点，但这三个非常
important pieces of concrete information about the pan.
关于平底锅的重要信息。
So, translation(in: UIView) is a function in the pan gesture
所以，平移(在UIView中)是平移手势的函数
recognizer where you can ask it,
你可以问这个问题，
how far has this pan moved since it started.
这个盘子从开始到现在有多远。
How far has it moved from the start as I'm moving around,
当我移动的时候，它从一开始移动了多远，
x and y, it's a CG point, so it's giving me the x and
x和y，它是一个重心，所以它给了我x和
y where it's moved to since it started.
y从它开始的地方开始。
Velocity says how fast is the finger moving.
速度表示手指移动的速度。
Is it kind of whipping it around or
这是一种鞭笞吗
is it going really slow?
进展真的很慢吗?
Because if it's going really slow,
因为如果速度很慢，
maybe you wanna do a very you know, small drawing.
也许你想做一个非常小的画。
And if he's whipping it really fast and
如果他真的快速地鞭打它
you just wanna you know, moves something around, who knows?
你只是想知道，移动一些东西，谁知道呢?
And then there's setTranslation,
然后调用setTranslation,
now this last one is kinda cool because
最后一个有点酷，因为
if you just know the start point and where it's moved to.
如果你知道起始点和它移动到哪里。
You're not really getting the incremental move with
你并没有真正得到增量的移动
each time you update,
每次你更新,
so you can actually set that translation to zero.
所以你可以把它设为零。
And then instead of getting the distance from the origin,
而不是距离原点的距离，
you're getting from the distance from the last time
从上次的距离开始
this was sent to you.
这是发给你的。
Cuz this handler's going to be sent to you over and
因为这个处理器会被发送给你
over as the pan moves around repeatedly.
当锅反复移动的时候。
Hundreds of times as you move move around, so
当你移动时，数百次
often you'll wanna set that translation back to zero,
通常你会把它设为0，
it gives you incremental panning.
它给你增加的平移。
You'll see that with some of the other concrete
你会看到一些其他的混凝土
Now, the abstract superclass, the UIGestureRecognizer,
现在，抽象的超类，UIGestureRecognizer，
ones as well.
的。
even though you don't make one it still is the superclass of
即使你不做，它仍然是超类的
these things.
这些事情。
And you do inherit,
和你继承,
especially this one very important var, Called state.
尤其是这个非常重要的变量，叫做状态。
And a state tells you the state of the gesture's,
一个状态告诉你这个手势的状态，
how it's being recognized.
它是如何被认可。
So all of these gesture recognizers start out in
所有的手势识别器都是从这里开始的
the state possible.
可能的状态。
It's possible this gesture could happen.
这个手势有可能会发生。
And then, once it starts if it's a continuous gesture
然后，一旦它开始，如果它是一个连续的手势
like a pan or a pinch you go to the state began.
就像一个平底锅，或者你去国家的时候。
So this isn't like, " a pan!, I think it's started".
所以这不是“一个平底锅!”我想这已经开始了。
So you'll get your handlers called and you can look at
你会让你的处理器被调用，你可以看看
the state of the recognizer and say, it began.
识别器的状态说，它开始了。
And then, every time the finger moves,
然后，每次手指移动，
it's gonna get changed.
它会得到改变。
It gets change, change, change, change, change,
它变了，变了，变了，变了，变了，
change, change.
改变,改变。
You're getting your handler called repeatedly and
你会不断地调用你的处理程序
no anything that's changing is those methods above,
没有任何改变是上述方法，
translation and also the state.
翻译和国家。
Moves to change.
行动改变。
And then, when the finger goes up, you get ended.
然后，当手指向上的时候，你就结束了。
You'll get your handler called and the state will be ended.
你会得到你的处理程序，然后状态就会结束。
Now, for a discrete gesture like a swipe,
现在，对于一个离散的手势，像滑动，
a swipe either happened or not.
滑动要么发生，要么不发生。
When you're looking at a swipe you don't get
当你看的时候，你不会得到
the swipe started and it's moving across the screen and
滑动开始，它在屏幕上移动
it comes off, no.
说,没有。
Either the swipe happened or not.
无论是否发生滑动。
So you would just get called once and
你只需要调用一次
the stage is gonna go straight to being ended or recognized.
舞台将会直接走向终结或被认可。
But you have to be a little bit careful of the states
但是你要注意这些状态
failed and cancelled.
失败,取消了。
Failed might be because you started a gesture and
失败可能是因为你开始了一个手势
then the system realized, my gosh,
然后系统意识到，我的天，
that wasn't a pan gesture, that was the start of a swipe.
那不是一个泛泛的手势，那是一种滑动的开始。
Or something like that.
之类的。
And so, it switches to a swipe.
所以，它切换到滑动。
So you could have canceled, and then the other one,
所以你可以取消，然后另一个，
or the failed, and then you also didn't have canceled.
或者失败了，然后你也没有取消。
You're in the middle of panning, phone call comes in,
你在淘金的过程中，电话打进来了，
takes over your screen, person says, hello, how you doing?
接管你的屏幕，有人说，你好，你好吗?
Well, clearly, that pan gesture was canceled.
很明显，这个手势被取消了。
So you could get that, as well.
你也可以得到这个。
So if you ever do anything, when you gesture ends,
所以如果你做任何事情，当你做手势的时候，
then you have to be careful to clean up when it fails, or
然后，当它失败时，你必须小心清理
gets canceled, as well.
被取消了。
So that's the state.
这是国家所有。
So let's take a look then, knowing what we know about pan
那么让我们来看看，了解我们对潘的了解
gestures, what the handler would look like.
手势，处理器会是什么样子。
So remember that the handler is called pan,
记住这个处理程序叫做pan，
recognizer is the argument there, and that is the pan
识别器是这里的参数，这是平移
gesture recognizer itself coming back to us.
手势识别器会自动回到我们身边。
And its state will be different,
它的状态会不同，
and we can ask it about translation and view and
我们可以问它关于平移和视图
all those things.
所有这些事情。
So the first thing we're gonna do is look at that state and
我们要做的第一件事就是看看那个状态
I'm going to do the same thing whether the pan is,
我要做同样的事情，
has changed or whether the finger went up.
发生了变化，或者手指是否向上。
That's kinda the last position of the pan,
这是pan的最后一个位置，
we're gonna do the exact same thing.
我们要做同样的事情。
Notice by the way I'm using this switch thing fallthrough,
注意，我使用这个开关的时候，
hopefully you got that in your reading assignment.
希望你们在阅读作业中得到了这个。
That basically just means that you wanna fall through to
那基本上只是意味着你想要失败
the next case cuz in a lot of languages that's the default,
下一个案例是很多语言中都是默认的，
but in Swift it's not the default,
但在Swift，它不是默认值，
you don't fall through.
你不会失败。
So fallthrough makes you fall through,
所以，fallthrough让你失败，
it's a special key word.
这是一个特别的关键词。
You could also say case.changed.ended: that
你也可以说case.changed。结束:
would probably be actually better.
可能会更好。
We'll do that in the demo.
我们会在demo中演示。
So if the pan moves a little or it ends, then I'm going to
所以如果平移了一点点，或者它结束了，那么我就会
get the translation from where we started at first
从我们开始的地方开始翻译
by asking for the translation in the pannable view.
通过在pannable视图中请求翻译。
That's the view the pan is having there.
这是pan在那里的观点。
You're almost always gonna ask for
你几乎总是要问
the translation in the pannable view.
在pannable视图中的翻译。
But you could ask for it in other views and
但你可以在其他视图中要求它
it will convert to that view's coordinate system if you want.
如果你想，它会转换到那个视图的坐标系统。
But almost always you're asking for
但几乎总是你在要求
the one in the pannable view.
在可控制的视图中。
Then, I'm gonna take that translation that I'm gonna
然后，我要把我要做的翻译
move and I'm gonna go do something with my app.
移动，我要用我的app做点什么。
Draw a line to,
画一条线,
if I'm tracking the finger with the line, or
如果我用这条线来跟踪手指
if I'm moving something,
如果我要搬东西,
I'm gonna move the thing to the new position.
我要把它移到新的位置。
Then, if I want, I can set translation to zero so
然后，如果我想，我可以把translation设为0
the next time this handler is called,
下一次调用这个处理程序时，
the translation is gonna be just the distance from
平移距离为
the last time it was called.
上次叫它的时候。
As opposed to the distance from where it all started.
而不是从它开始的距离。
Where the pan started.
锅里开始的地方。
So that's it.
这就是它。
That's how a handler works, it's easy.
这就是处理程序的工作方式，很简单。
Let's talk a little bit about some of the other concrete
让我们来谈谈另一些具体的东西
gestures.
手势。
So I put my fingers down, two fingers on the screen.
所以我把手指放下，两个手指在屏幕上。
Now, the scale is 1.0.
现在，刻度是1。0。
If I put my fingers twice as far apart,
如果我把手指分开两倍，
now the scale is 2.0.
现在规模是2.0。
If I go down to half as small now, the scale is 0.5.
如果现在减小到一半，刻度是0。5。
So that's what pinch is doing.
这就是缩放的作用。
It just constantly reporting what the scale is,
它只是不断地报道规模是什么，
relative to what the pinch started.
相对于缩放的开始。
Now, that scale is not read-only var, so
这个比例不是只读var
you can reset it as well.
你也可以重置它。
And then, you'll get incremental scale.
然后，你会得到增量的规模。
How much the scale has changed since the last time?
自上次以来，规模有多大变化?
There's almost like you keep resetting the initial finger
几乎就像你不停地重新设置手指
down, to scale, if you set that scale to one.
向下，按比例，如果你把这个比例设置为1。
That's how you can get incremental scale.
这就是如何得到增量的规模。
We'll do that in the demo as well.
我们在demo中也会这样做。
And then, you also get velocity.
然后，你也得到了速度。
How many points for a second or whatever this thing is, or
这一秒有多少个点，或者是什么
not really a point fact.
这并不是一个真正的问题。
It's a scale factor.
这是一个比例因子。
The percent of scale is changing,
比例在变化，
how fast it's changing per second.
每秒变化有多快。
There's also a rotation gesture that's two fingers
还有一个旋转手势，两个手指
down, like turning a knob.
就像转动一个旋钮。
Keep the two fingers down.
把这两个手指放下来。
You turn them.
你把他们。
You get the rotation there.
就得到了旋转。
The rotation is in radians.
旋转是弧度。
Again, it's not read only so you could reset it and
同样，它不是只读的所以你可以重置它
get the incremental turning.
增量转动。
And you also get the velocity and radians per second.
你也会得到速度和每秒弧度。
How fast the person is turning their knob.
这个人转动旋钮的速度有多快。
There's also SwipeGesture, and again this is discrete so
还有swipe手势，这也是离散的
your handler's only gonna be called once.
你的处理器只会被调用一次。
If it recognizes this gesture.
如果它意识到这个手势。
Now, because of that,
现在,因此,
you have to configure a SwipeGesture recognizer.
您必须配置一个swipe手势识别器。
You create it and
你创建它,
then you wanna set bars here like direction.
然后你想在这里设置像方向这样的。
You wanna left swipe, right swipe, up, down.
你想要向左滑动，右击，向上，向下。
And how many fingers?
有多少个手指?
Two finger swipe?
两个手指滑动?
Three finger swipe?
三个手指滑动?
You set all that up when you create it because then it's
当你创建它的时候，你设置了所有这些，因为它是
One finger swipe?
一个手指滑动?
just gonna be looking for that.
只是为了寻找那个。
And when it finds it, it's gonna call your handler once.
当它找到它的时候，它会调用你的处理器一次。
Cuz it's discrete.
因为它是离散的。
Then there's tap gesture, similar to the swipe gesture
然后是tap手势，类似于滑动手势
in that you have to configure it.
你必须配置它。
Number of taps, like is it a double tap and
水龙头的数量，就像一个双龙头
is it two finger tap, you do that.
是两个手指轻拍，你这样做。
And then, it's gonna call, this is not purely a discrete
然后，它会调用，这不仅仅是一个离散的
gesture, like SwipeGesture, really you're looking for
手势，像游泳姿势，真的是你在找
the state ended with a tap as well, but
这个州也以tap告终，但是
still you have to preconfigure it like a swipe, so
但你还是要像刷卡一样预配置它
it behaves almost exactly like a discrete gesture.
它的行为几乎完全像一个离散的手势。
So hopefully this will make a lot more sense when we show in
所以希望当我们展示的时候，这会更有意义
the demo here, our demo we're gonna add three gestures,
演示，我们的演示，我们要添加三个手势，
one is a pinch, that's just gonna make the face bigger and
一个是缩放，这将会使脸部变得更大
Which has nothing to do with a model that view only so
这与一个只有视图的模型没有关系
smaller.
小。
we're gonna put that handler in the view.
我们将把这个处理程序放在视图中。
And then, we gonna do pan, moving around.
然后，我们要做平移，移动。
Actually no, we're gonna swipe instead of pan.
不，我们要用刷卡，而不是用平底锅。
Let's use swipe.
让我们用刷。
We do swipe and we swipe up to make our face happier or
我们刷卡，向上滑动，让我们的脸更快乐
swipe down to make it sadder.
向下滑动，让它更悲伤。
And we'll have tab to open and close your eyes.
我们会让tab打开，闭上你的眼睛。
How about that?
怎么样?
And those last two are obviously gonna affect
最后两个显然会产生影响
the model, so the'll have to be handled by the controller.
模型，所以必须由控制器来处理。
So le's go back to our code where we were here and
所以，le回到我们在这里的代码
how we can do this.
我们该怎么做。
Le's do the pinch first.
先缩放。
Now, the pinch does't affect the model, so
现在，缩放不会影响模型
it can be handled by the view.
它可以由视图来处理。
So le's actually go over to our view and
因此，le实际上是去了我们的视图
start by writing a handler for a pinch.
首先编写一个缩放处理程序。
I'm gonna call this handler func changeScale because
我把它命名为handler func changeScale，因为
that's what it's gonna do, it's gonna be a pinch.
这就是它将要做的，它将会是一个缩放。
So it's gonna change the scale of our head.
所以它会改变我们大脑的大小。
And I'm gonna say byReactingTo a pinchRecognizer,
我要说的是，对一个pinch识别器，
Which will be UI pinch recognizer,
这将是UI缩放识别器，
pinch gesture recognizer, there we go.
缩放手势识别器，好了。
So this is gonna be my handler.
这是我的处理器。
So it's gonna get this pinch sent back to me all the time.
所以它会一直给我发送这个缩放。
I'm not gonna look at that pinch of scale to know
我不打算看这个缩放比例
how much to scale my own scale.
多大程度上我自己的规模。
So I'm gonna switch on the pinch recognizer's state.
我将打开缩放识别器的状态。
Remember, it inherits that from UI gesture recognizer,
记住，它是从ui手势识别器继承的，
which is the super class of this.
这是它的超类。
And in the case that it is changed, so
在这种情况下，它改变了
the pinch has changed, or
缩放改变了，或者
if it's ended, which means the user lifted the fingers off.
如果它结束了，这意味着用户将手指移开。
Neither of those cases I'm gonna adjust my scale
这两种情况都不会调整我的量表
by whatever the scale is of the pinchRecognizer.
按比例来衡量pinch识别器。
Simple as that.
就这么简单。
Now the thing about this though, what if
现在关于这个的问题，如果
I start my pinch here 1.0, and I move it just a little bit.
我在这里开始缩放1。0，然后移动一点点。
Okay, fine.
好的,很好。
My scale gets moved just a little bit.
我的尺度移动了一点点。
What if I moved all the way out to scale 2.0?
如果我一直走到2.0版呢?
Now my face gets 2.0.
现在我的脸得到2.0。
Now what if I move it out to 2.1?
如果把它移动到1。2呢?
This code's gonna make my face go from 2.1 to 4.2 you see.
这段代码会让我的脸从2.1到4.2。
So I need to keep resetting this scale back to 1 all
所以我需要把这个比例重新设置为1
the time so I'm getting incremental scale changes.
时间是变化的。
So I'm gonna say pinch recognizer .scale = 1.
我用缩放识别器。规模= 1。
So I'm just constantly resetting.
所以我一直在重新设置。
Every time this gets called, and
每次都被调用
I move my scale up, I'm gonna reset the scale so
我移动我的刻度，我将重置缩放比例
that I'm starting at one again with my pinch.
我要重新开始。
That gives me incremental scaling there.
这给了我增量的缩放。
And of course we have to handle all the other cases
当然我们还要处理其他的情况
of the state.
的状态。
But I'm not gonna do anything.
但我什么都不想做。
So I'm not gonna do anything when the pinch starts.
所以当缩放开始时，我什么都不做。
If it gets cancelled, I don't care.
如果它被取消了，我不在乎。
I'll just leave it whatever scale it was
不管它的规模是多少
in at the time, etc.
在当时，等等。
So I don't need to really handle any other cases.
所以我不需要处理其他的情况。
So that's it.
这就是它。
The handlers are super easy to write.
处理程序非常容易编写。
And this scale by the way,
这个尺度，
everyone understands, is this scale right here, this bar.
每个人都明白，这个比例就是这个。
This is our scale.
这是我们的规模。
Questions about that?
问题吗?
So now we have a handler.
现在我们有了一个处理器。
We have someone to handle when a pinch happens in the view.
在视图中出现缩放时，我们需要有人处理。
Now all we need to do is add a recognizer that recognizes
现在我们需要添加一个识别器
a pinch, and calls the handler.
一个缩放，并调用处理器。
So we're gonna do that up here in our face views
我们将在我们的面部视图中做这个
didSet, because this is the first time we got a hold of
didSet，因为这是我们第一次得到
that face view, and I want the face view to be the one
那面视图，我想让它的面视图为1
that is recognizing this pinch.
这就是意识到这一点。
So let's start by creating the handlers, so
让我们从创建处理程序开始
I'm going to create a local variabilities to make it clear
我要创建一个局部变量来说明
to my handler.
我的处理程序。
It's a hashtag selector and its the faceView method,
它是一个hashtag选择器和它的faceView方法，
changeScalebyReactingTo, that's my handler.
changeScalebyReactingTo,那是我的处理程序。
And then I am going to create a recognizer here,
然后我要在这里创建一个识别器，
a pinch recognizer and
一撮识别器和
it's going to be a UIPinchGestureRecognizer and
它将是一个UIPinchGestureRecognizer和
of course we need the target and the action.
我们当然需要目标和行动。
That's all we need to create a recognizer.
我们需要创建一个识别器。
The target is going to be the faceView,
目标是faceView，
it's gonna handle this thing itself, and
它会自己处理这个问题
the action is gonna be this handler.
动作将是这个处理器。
That's it.
就是这样。
Now we just need to take the faceView and
现在我们只需要使用faceView
add GestureRecognizer, the pinchRecognizer.
添加手势识别器,pinchRecognizer。
And by doing that,
通过这样做,
face view is gonna start recognizing pinches.
face view将会开始识别pinches。
And when it recognizes one, it's gonna send this handler
当它识别了一个，它就会发送这个处理器
message right here to the face view.
这里的信息到face view。
Now, if you
现在,如果你
hope this is gonna work, let's see.
希望这能起作用，让我们看看。
When you might ask, by the way,
顺便说一下，你可能会问，
if I have a mouse here, how do I do a pinch?
如果我这里有一只老鼠，我如何缩放?
In my thing, okay?
在我的东西,好吗?
Well the magic there is option.
神奇之处就在这里。
If you press option, and look,
如果你按下选项，看，
I haven't even touched anything,
我什么都没碰过，
see I have two things right there.
这里有两个东西。
And they kinda stay the same apart.
它们保持着相同的距离。
You can also do option shift, and they'll offset them, so
你也可以选择移动，他们会抵消它们，所以
you can pinch anywhere you want.
你可以在任何你想要的地方缩放。
So anyway, do that.
无论如何,这样做。
No, it's not working.
不,它不是工作。
See that? How could that possibly be?
看到了吗?这怎么可能呢?
Well, let's take a moment here and debug this.
我们先来调试一下。
Why would this not be working?
为什么它不工作呢?
I put that pinch gesture.
我把那个缩放手势。
I added it.
我补充道。
I have a handler.
我有一个处理程序。
Let's start by going to our FaceView and
我们先从FaceView开始
putting a break point right here in our handler Bar.
在处理程序条中设置断点。
And let's see if it's actually handling it okay.
让我们看看它是否真的处理好了。
So I'm going to go back to here,
我要回到这里，
I'm going to get my option ready, pinch.
我要准备好我的选择。
Alright!
好吧!
It broke.
就坏了。
It's definitely calling my handler.
它肯定是在调用我的处理器。
So what's the problem?
所以有什么问题?
Let's do nothing.
我们什么都不做。
Let's say let's print our scale and
我们来打印刻度
see if our scale is being change.
看看我们的规模是否正在改变。
I'm just gonna put a little print line in here.
我在这里画一条线。
Use a combination of break points here and
在这里使用断点的组合
doing print debugging.
做打印调试。
And let's,
让我们,
let's see if the scale is actually being changed.
让我们看看这个比例是否真的改变了。
Here we go.
我们开始吧。
Again option key, and, it looks like it is.
再一次选择键，它看起来是这样的。
I see something in the background there.
我在背景里看到了一些东西。
Sure enough look at that.
当然看了。
Half, double, it's working perfectly.
一半，双倍，它工作得很完美。
Why is it not redrawing that face.
为什么不重新画那张脸。
Can anyone thing why it's not redrawing.
谁能解释为什么它不能被重新绘制。
Cuz we know it's working.
因为我们知道它在起作用。
It's because when you change a var, like scale, right
因为当你改变一个var，比如scale，对
here it does not automatically know to redraw your view.
在这里它不会自动知道重新绘制你的视图。
That scale is changing fine.
这种规模正在改变。
But the last time draw was called was when this first
但上一次抽签是在第一次
thing was drawn, you know, this method we have down here
我们画的这个方法
in the FaceView called draw CGRect.
在FaceView中，名为draw CGRect。
This thing?
这个东西吗?
This was called when it was first drawn and
这是它第一次绘制时被调用的
it's never been called again.
它从来没有被再次调用过。
So without this being called there's no other way to draw
所以没有这个被称为没有别的方法来画
my face I told you this is the only way to draw.
我告诉过你这是唯一的方法。
So we have to get this to get called.
所以我们要把它叫做。
And how are we gonna do that?
我们要怎么做呢?
Well we're just gonna slide right up here to scale, and
我们先从这里开始缩放，然后
any time scale get called, we're gonna do a didSet.
任何时间尺度被调用，我们都会做didSet。
Okay, and inside here we're going to
在这里，我们要
cause ourself to get drawn.
让我们自己来画。
Now how do I do that?
怎么做呢?
Do I call draw like that?
我可以这样叫吗?
No, I see a lot of shaking heads no and absolutely not.
不，我看到很多摇头表示不，绝对不是。
Of course we never call draw.
当然，我们从来不叫平局。
We get huge trouble if we do that.
如果我们这样做，我们就会遇到大麻烦。
What do we call instead?
我们怎么称呼?
Anyone remember from the slides?
有人记得幻灯片吗?
SetNeedsDisplay.
SetNeedsDisplay。
So we're telling the system something about us has
所以我们告诉系统一些关于我们的东西
changed, we need to be re-displayed.
改变了，我们需要重新展示。
So please, at your earliest convenience, re-display us.
所以，请在您方便的时候，重新展示我们。
And that's what it's gonna do.
这就是它的作用。
And in fact, we want this on all of our things here.
事实上，我们想要的是所有的东西。
Any time any of these public things get changed by someone,
任何时候这些公共事物都被某人改变了，
we want to re-display.
我们想在内部将。
Let's put this comment up here.
我们把这个注释放在这里。
So this is very common to have this little snippet of code
这是一个很常见的代码片段
after any var, that when you change it,
在任何var之后，当你改变它的时候，
would change the way things look.
会改变事物的外观。
Now when we run we can actually go back here and
当我们运行时，我们可以回到这里
get rid of this print.
把这打印出来。
Pretty confident it's
很有信心的
going to work now.
现在去工作。
Here I go on option again, and sure enough, look, our scale.
在这里，我再次选择，当然，看，我们的规模。
Since our scale changes here, that setNeedsDisplay is
因为我们这里的尺度变化，所以setNeedsDisplay是
asking to draw and iOS is accommodating us by drawing.
要求绘画和iOS可以通过绘画来适应我们。
That's pretty cool,
这是很酷,
that was quite simple to put in that gesture to do that.
这样做很简单。
So let's go back now to our controller, and
现在回到控制器
think about doing a gesture like a tap, to open the eyes.
想一下做个手势，像水龙头一样，让眼睛睁开。
Now again, the view could be the handler for that.
现在，视图可以是这个的处理程序。
It arguably knows how to open an close its eyes.
可以说，它知道如何闭上眼睛。
But if we made the view be the handler for a tap, and it
但如果我们让视图成为一个tap的处理器，那么它
opened the eyes, it would get out of sync with the model.
打开眼睛，它就会与模型不同步。
Cuz the model is what says whether the eyes are open,
因为模型是说眼睛是否睁开，
not the face view.
不是脸的观点。
Face view is a slave.
Face view是一个奴隶。
It's a minion of the controller,
它是控制器的一个minion，
it's supposed to do what the controller wants, so
它应该做控制器想要的，所以
we can't do that.
我们不能这样做。
So we're gonna have to have the controller handle a tap,
所以我们要让控制器控制水龙头，
and change it in the model.
然后在模型中改变它。
And then it'll automatically
然后它会自动
update in the UI because of this line of code right here.
在UI中更新因为这一行代码。
Any time we change our model it's gonna update our UI.
任何时候改变模型都会更新UI。
So we're gonna just have to have a handler for
我们需要一个处理程序
tap that just changes our model.
点击它可以改变我们的模式。
And that's all it needs to do.
这就是它需要做的。
Let's try that handler first.
让我们先试试那个处理器。
Let's call that handler, how about toggleEyes
让我们调用这个处理程序，toggleEyes
cuz we're gonna tap and it's gonna with the eyes.
因为我们要用它，用眼睛。
If its opened it'll close, close it'll open.
如果它打开，它将关闭，关闭它将打开。
And toggleEyes is a tapGestureRecognizer thing,
toggleEyes是一个tapGestureRecognizer的东西，
so I'm gonna say byReacting to a tapRecognizer
所以我要对一个tap识别器做出反应
which is a type UITapGestureRecognizer.
这是一种UITapGestureRecognizer。
And here I'm just gonna say,
这里我要说，
if the tapRecognizer.state is ended.
如果tapRecognizer。状态是结束了。
So the tap happened.
所以发生了水龙头。
Then I'm gonna let eyes, which is FacialExpression.Eyes,
然后我会让眼睛，这是面部表情，眼睛，
just so that you know what type that is,
这样你就知道那是什么类型了，
equal whatever my current expression's eyes are,
不管我现在的表情是什么，
if the current expressions eyes are closed, then I'm
如果现在的表情是闭着的，那么我就是
going to have them be open, otherwise they will be closed.
要把它们打开，否则它们就会被关闭。
So I'm just toggling them.
我只是在跟他们说。
So eyes now which is of type FacialExpression.Eyes,
所以眼睛现在是面部表情，眼睛，
it's got the opposite or whatever the old one had.
它和旧的是相反的。
Now, I'm gonna set my model to equal a new facial expression.
现在，我要将我的模型设为一个新的面部表情。
That new facial expression's eyes
那新面孔的眼神
are gonna be this new eyes I just calculated.
是我刚刚计算出来的新眼睛。
And the mouth is gonna be whatever the old mouth was.
嘴巴就会像原来的嘴巴一样。
I'm not doing anything to the mouth, so I'm just gonna say
我没有做任何事，所以我只是想说
expression.mouth, for the old one.
表达式。嘴巴，这是旧的。
So here I'm changing my model and
这里我改变了模型
that's gonna cause this didSet to happen.
这将会导致这个didSet发生。
It's gonna re-draw my view and
它会重新绘制我的视图
the eyes are gonna be the opposite of what they were.
眼睛会和他们的眼睛相反。
So that's the handler.
这是处理程序。
That's gonna handle that.
的处理。
So now we have to add a tap gesture recognizer
现在我们需要添加一个tap手势识别器
to our face view.
我们的脸。
So this time let's just say let tapRecognizer =
所以这次我们说，让tap识别器=
UITapGestureRecognizer.
UITapGestureRecognizer。
And as always we just specify target and selector.
和往常一样，我们只指定目标和选择器。
So the target this time is not faceView,
所以这次的目标不是faceView，
up here it was faceView.
在上面，它是faceView。
Now the target is myself.
现在目标是我自己。
And the action is going to be,
这个动作是，
again I can say faceView controller or
我还是可以用faceView控制器
I can indicate self dot, we'll do that, toggle eyes.
我可以画出self。。
And we need to put around this #selector.
我们需要把这个# selector放到这里。
Cuz we need to turn it into that particular selector.
因为我们需要把它转换成特定的选择器。
Then again, I don't actually need that self in there,
再一次，我实际上不需要那个self，
Looks a little better cuz it defaults to my own methods.
看起来好一点，因为它默认了我自己的方法。
I can just do that.
我可以这么做。
So we got the tap recognizer created.
所以我们创建了tap识别器。
Now we have to configure the tap recognizer
现在我们需要配置tap识别器
because we want it to happen on single taps.
因为我们想让它发生在单个熄灯号上。
So we could say for example numberOfTapsRequired = 1,
所以我们可以说，例如numberOfTapsRequired = 1，
that happens to be the default, so probably I won't
这恰好是默认值，所以我可能不会
need to actually say that, but we'll do it anyway.
实际上我们需要这么说，但我们还是会这么做。
And now we need to turn it on and we do that by adding
现在我们需要打开它，通过添加
a gestureRecognizer to the FaceView.
一个gestureRecognizer到FaceView。
If you don't do this step of adding it to some view
如果你不这样做的话，把它添加到某个视图中
then that view is not going to be recognizing this.
那么这个观点就不会被认可。
So it's not gonna be doing anything.
所以它不会做任何事情。
Just an easy step to kind of forget.
只是一个简单的步骤来忘记。
All right, so let's
好吧,让我们
see if that works.
看看这个行不行。
All right, so tap, it's working.
好的，点击，它在工作。
Every time I tap, it opens and closes the eyes.
每次我点击，它就会打开和关闭眼睛。
And it's changing it in the model.
它在模型中改变了它。
So it changes the model,
它改变了模型，
that causes the update UI to happen, this update UI does
这会导致更新UI发生，这个更新UI会发生
does this little thing to update the eyes.
做这个小事情来更新眼睛。
When it calls eyes open over here okay, eyesOpen.
当它的眼睛睁开的时候，眼睛睁开。
When it gets set, it calls NeedsDisplay,
当它被设置时，它调用NeedsDisplay，
which causes the thing to redraw.
这导致了重新绘制。
Everyone got that chain of events?
每个人都有一连串的事件吗?
Let's do one other one here.
我们再做一个。
Which is to do a swipe.
那就是刷卡。
So I'm gonna have a swipe, where swiping up makes
我要扫一下，在哪里刷
our face happier and swiping down makes it sadder.
我们的脸更快乐，向下滑动使它更悲伤。
So this has to be handled in the controller.
所以这个必须在控制器中处理。
Why?
为什么?
Because this is affecting the model.
因为这影响了模型。
Happiness is in the model.
幸福在于榜样。
So I'm gonna have a func called increaseHappiness.
所以我要有一个叫做“增加快乐”的func。
It's just going to set the expression equal to
它只是将表达式设为等于
the existing expression but happier.
既有表情，但更快乐。
I'll do a func decreaseHappiness,
我会做一个减少幸福的方法，
i's gonna be the opposite,
我将会相反，
expression = the current expression but sadder.
表达式=当前表达式，但更难过。
And these vars here, happier and
这些vars，更快乐
sadder, those are in the FacialExpression, right here.
sadder，这些在FacialExpression中，在这里。
You can look at those later to see how they work.
稍后您可以查看这些内容以了解它们是如何工作的。
But basically the're just creating a new
但基本上只是创造了一个新的
FacialExpression where the mouth is happier or
面部表情，嘴巴更快乐的表情
the mouth is sadder.
口腔是悲伤。
And then the mouth knows how to be happy or sad or
然后，嘴巴知道如何开心或悲伤
it's using this raw value mechanism in enum, hopefully
希望在enum中使用这个原始的值机制
you've figured that out in your reading assignment.
你已经在阅读作业中找到了答案。
This is a great opportunity to go figure it out if you
如果你可以的话，这是一个很好的机会
didn't.
没有。
Back in our controller here, we now have these handlers.
回到控制器中，现在有了这些处理程序。
Notice these handlers have no argument.
注意这些处理程序没有参数。
Why do these handlers not have an argument,
为什么这些处理器没有参数，
like this ByReactingTo guy down here.
就像这里的人一样。
Because a swipe gesture is discrete, so
因为滑动手势是离散的，所以
we never have to look at the swipe gesture when it happens,
我们从来不用看它发生时的滑动手势，
we know it happened and that's all we need to know.
我们知道它发生了，这就是我们需要知道的。
So these handlers do not ever need to look at the state or
因此这些处理程序不需要查看状态
anything like that, like a tap gesture or a swipe gesture or
任何类似的东西，比如轻击手势或滑动手势
a hand gesture.
一个手势。
Let's add these guys to there, so
把这些项加到这里
I'm gonna let swipeUpRecognizer =
我要让swiUNK precognizer =
UISwipeGestureRecognizer, again, target and action.
UISwipeGestureRecognizer,目标和行动。
Again, the target is myself because it affects the model.
再次，目标是我自己，因为它影响模型。
And I'm gonna have this be the selector increaseHappiness
这就是选择器增加幸福度
because this is swipe up.
因为这是向上滑动。
Okay, now I have to configure it.
现在我要配置它。
SwipeUpRecognizer's direction is up, and
swiUNK precognizer的方向是向上的
now I'm gonna add it,
现在我要添加它，
faceView.addGestureRecognizer- (swipeUpRecognizer).
faceView。addGestureRecognizer——(swipeUpRecognizer)。
And since swipeDown is so similar,
因为swipeDown是如此相似，
I'm just going to copy and paste here.
我要复制粘贴。
Copy and paste.
复制和粘贴。
And we will change swipe up to be swipe down.
我们将会改变滑动，向下滑动。
And of course, the direction here now is down.
当然，这里的方向是向下的。
And it's decreaseHappiness and so I decrease.
它减少了幸福，所以我减少了。
So I've added these two recognizers, up and
我把这两个识别器加起来了
down swiping.
刷。
And they're going to increase and
它们会增加
decrease our happiness in the model.
降低我们在模型中的幸福感。
And when the model changes, update UI is called.
当模型发生变化时，更新UI被调用。
We're gonna look up mouth curvature in that dictionary.
我们会在字典里查到口曲率。
We're gonnaset the mouth curvature,
我们的嘴是弯曲的，
that's gonna do the didSet, we're in good shape.
这是didSet，我们的状态很好。
So here we have a pretty sad guy, we'll open his eyes,
所以我们有一个很伤心的人，我们会睁开他的眼睛，
then we'll close, no leave them open.
然后我们将关闭，不让它们打开。
Now we're gonna make him happier, and
现在我们要让他更快乐
happier, and happier.
幸福和快乐。
Woo, he's really happy!
哇,他真的很快乐!
And swiping down, no, not so happy after all.
然后向下滑动，不，不太高兴。
So that's it for gestures.
这就是手势。
Gestures are super-simple and super-powerful cuz all
手势非常简单，而且超级强大
the logic going into detecting was that a swipe, or was that
用于检测的逻辑是滑动，或者是
a pan, or what was that, was all done for you by iOS.
一个平移，或者是什么，都是由iOS完成的。
Back to our
回到我们的
slides.
幻灯片。
Time to talk about building bigger apps,
是时候讨论构建更大的应用了，
apps where we're gonna have multiple MVCs involved.
我们将有多个mvc的应用程序。
Not just our calculator MVC, but multiple MVCs.
不只是我们的计算器MVC，而是多个MVC。
Not just our face view controller MVC, but
不只是我们的face view controller MVC，而是
multiple MVCs.
多个mvc。
So I showed you this picture from the MVC discussion and
我给你们看了这张MVC讨论的图片
you can see that the MVCs relationship to each other is
可以看到，mvc之间的关系是
that one or more MVCs is part of the view of another MVC.
一个或多个MVC是另一个MVC视图的一部分。
So let's see how that happens.
我们来看看这是怎么发生的。
We combine these MVCs using, (I don't wanna say special,
我们把这些mvc结合起来(我不想说特别，
because you could write your own), but
因为你可以自己写，但是
built-in MVCs that come with iOS.
内置的mvc，与iOS兼容。
And these MVCs are built
这些mvc构建
using other MVCs as part of their view.
使用其他mvc作为视图的一部分。
So, yes you can build your own.
所以，你可以建立你自己的。
So, for example, here's the three that we do most of our
举个例子，这是我们做的三件事
building with here or pretty much all of our building,
在这里或几乎所有的建筑中，
multiple MVCs.
多个mvc。
There's the TabBarController, a SplitViewController and
这是TabBarController,SplitViewController
a NavigationController.
一个导航控制器。
So I'm gonna go into detail here about how each of these
这里我将详细讲解每一个
controllers, are controllers of MVCs
控制器，是mvc的控制器
whose view is other MVCs.
谁的观点是其他的mvc。
So here's a TabBarController for example.
这是一个TabBarController。
If you look at what you see up there,
如果你看你在上面看到的，
there are two MVCs on that screen, two.
屏幕上有两个mvc。
One MVC is the TabBarController.
一个MVC是TabBarController。
It's what's drawing the little icons at the bottom.
这是底部的小图标。
You see those icons at the bottom, those four icons?
你看到那些图标在底部，那四个图标?
That MVC is doing that.
MVC就是这么做的。
The other MVC is the thing surrounded in yellow,
另一个MVC是用黄色包围的，
a dashboard MVC, whatever that is,
一个仪表板MVC，不管它是什么，
something in the health app here or something.
在健康应用程序中。
That is drawn by a completely different MVC,
这是由一个完全不同的MVC绘制的，
the dashboard MVC.
仪表板MVC。
But notice how it's drawing inside the view
但注意它是如何在视图中绘制的
of the tab bar controller.
的标签栏控制器。
So, you're already seeing here how we're building an MVC out
你已经看到了我们如何构建一个MVC
of other MVCs.
其他的mvc。
The tab bar controller has an MVC built into its view.
标签栏控制器有一个MVC内置的视图。
Now, what's interesting is this is very object oriented
有趣的是，这是面向对象的
in that those buttons along the bottom, both the icon and
在底部的那些按钮，图标和
the text on and if they had a badge,
文本，如果他们有徽章，
that would be there too.
那也会在那里。
Those are actually not being set in the TabBarController,
这些实际上不是在TabBarController中设置的，
the TabBarController is grabbing them from
TabBarController正在抓取它们
the dashboard MVC.
仪表板MVC。
Grabs them from a var in the dashboard MVC,
从在仪表板MVC中的var中获取它们，
it's a view UI controller bar called TabBarItem.
它是一个名为TabBarItem的视图UI控制器条。
And TabBarItem has things like Badges, and titles, and icons,
TabBarItem有徽章，标题和图标，
things like that.
类似这样的事情。
And of course, we can have more MVCs in the tab bar if I
当然，如果我，我们可以在标签栏中有更多的mvc
click on that second icon right there,
点击第二个图标，
I get a different MVC filling up this space at the top.
我得到了一个不同的MVC填充这个空间的顶部。
So now, we've seen three MVCs so
现在，我们已经看到了3个mvc
far, dashboard, health data, and the TabBarController.
远、仪表板、健康数据和TabBarController。
Right, now by the way, if you get too many tabs, if you put
对了，如果你有太多的标签
six MVCs, for example, into a tab bar controller,
例如，6个mvc，到一个标签栏控制器，
then you get a little more "..." icon on the right, and
然后你再多一点……右边的图标，还有
you can click that and the user can get at those.
你可以点击它，用户可以得到这些。
So a tab bar controller could have more than five MVCs.
所以标签栏控制器可以有5个以上的mvc。
But if you start getting more than five,
但如果你开始得到5个以上，
the UI gets a little clunky because their user is having
用户界面因为用户的存在而变得有点笨拙
to go over and click that more to get to the other one.
为了走到另一个地方，点击它。
I kinda recommend if you have a tab bar,
我建议如果你有一个标签栏，
don't put more than five MVCs in there.
不要放多于5个mvc。
So the question is, when we have the icons at the bottom
问题是，当我们有底部的图标时
and like, the icons and the titles there.
比如，图标和标题。
And I said that it's getting that from the MVCs that
我说这是从mvc那里得到的
are being shown.
被显示。
The question is, is the embedded
问题是，嵌入式的
MVC, like the health data one, or the dashboard one, is it
MVC，像health data one，或dashboard one，就是它
getting the button and the title there from the model?
从模型中获取按钮和标题?
And the answer is, that's up to that MVC.
答案是，这取决于MVC。
Some MVCs might well do that, probably most are not because
一些风险投资公司很可能做到这一点，可能大多数不是因为
it's kinda more of a UI thing what the icon and the text is.
它更像是一个UI，图标和文本。
Probably not part of the model, especially the icon.
可能不是模型的一部分，尤其是图标。
Unlikely to be in the model.
不太可能出现在模型中。
We have more MVCs for a total of five MVCs on the screen.
我们有更多的mvc，在屏幕上总共有5个mvc。
The tab bar controller and
标签栏控制器和
these four MVCs that are each of the tabs.
这四个mvc是每个选项卡。
So this is the simplest way to combine MVCs.
这是组合mvc最简单的方法。
But do you see what I mean when I say that these other
但你明白我说的这些是什么意思吗
MVCs are part of the view of the tab bar controller.
MVCs是标签栏控制器视图的一部分。
They're actually even their views are embedded physically
实际上，他们的观点也被植入了身体
embedded inside the tab bar controller's view.
嵌入在标签栏控制器的视图中。
So that's the simplest one.
这是最简单的。
Let's talk about the next simplest one,
我们来讨论下一个最简单的，
which is split view controller.
这是分屏视图控制器。
So split view controllers is two MVCs side by side.
分屏视图控制器是两个mvc。
You get to see them both on screen at the same time,
你可以同时在屏幕上看到它们，
at least in landscape you do.
至少在风景中是这样的。
This one on the left here is a calculator MVC.
左边的这个是计算器MVC。
It doesn't look much like yours but
它看起来不像你的，但是
you can imagine that's a calculator MVC.
你可以想象这是一个计算器MVC。
That MVC,
MVC,
we call the master MVC of the split view controller.
我们调用了分屏视图控制器的主MVC。
And then on the other side there's a whole different MVC,
然后在另一边有一个完全不同的MVC，
completely and utterly different.
完全不同。
This one happens to be a graph of
这个恰好是一个图
what's in the calculator MVC.
计算器MVC里有什么。
And this is gonna look very similar
这看起来非常相似
to your homework assignment, because that is assignment 3.
作业中，因为这是作业3。
To build a graphing calculator,
要建立一个图形计算器，
you're gonna be putting in a split view and
你将会有一个分屏视图
doing all the things I'm talking about today,
我今天所讲的一切，
so pay attention.
引起我们的注意。
So that we call a detail.
我们称之为细节。
The reason we call that a detail,
我们称之为细节的原因，
is almost always the right side,
几乎总是正确的，
which is larger usually, whatever's in it happens
通常情况下，会发生什么
to be controlled by what's on the left by the master.
由主人左边的东西控制。
And that would be true here.
在这里也是成立的。
Cuz the graph on the right is showing whatever is in
因为右边的图显示的是
the calculator on the left.
左边的计算器。
So if you change something in the calculator on the left and
如果你在计算器左边改变一些东西
hit its graphing button, it changes the details.
点击它的绘图按钮，它会改变细节。
So the master is controlling the detail in that way.
所以大师就是这样控制细节的。
Now, and this is what it looks like when these things
这就是这些东西的样子
are side-by-side in landscape mode.
景观模式是并排的。
But what if you switch over to portrait?
但如果你切换到竖屏呢?
Well, in portrait it just shows you the detail, but
在竖屏中，它只是展示了细节，但是
you can swipe from the left and get the master to come
你可以从左边滑动，让主人来
out on top of it and then do whatever you want.
在上面，然后做任何你想做的事情。
It still updates the utility and
它仍然更新实用程序和
you can swipe it out of the way.
你可以把它从路上划掉。
So that's split view controller.
这是分屏视图控制器。
Super simple.
超级简单。
Again, hopefully you're seeing that there are three MVCs
希望你能看到有三个mvc
The split view controller's MVC, and these master and
拆分视图控制器的MVC，以及这些master和
up here.
在这里。
detail MVCs.
细节mvc。
The master details serve as the view of
大师的细节是可以理解的
that split view controller.
分屏视图控制器。
Notice that the split view controller itself has no UI.
注意，拆分视图控制器本身没有UI。
It doesn't actually draw anything in the view,
它并没有在视图中绘制任何东西，
it just uses the UI or the view of these MVCs to draw.
它只是使用UI或者这些mvc的视图来绘制。
I guess, it draws the vertical line between the two,
我想，它画出了两者之间的垂直线，
that's probably drawn by the split view.
这可能是由分屏视图绘制的。
The most complicated one and
最复杂的一个
the most commonly used one, is a navigation controller.
最常用的是导航控制器。
Another MVC that uses other MVCs in its view.
另一个在视图中使用其他MVC的MVC。
So, here we see two MVCs on this screen,
在这个屏幕上，我们看到两个mvc，
navigation controller based MVC.
基于导航控制器的MVC。
And it's showing another MVC,
它显示的是另一个MVC，
which I'm calling the all settings MVC.
我调用了所有的设置MVC。
In this particular view that you're looking at.
在这个特定的视图中。
See on the top there's a gray bar that says
在上面有一个灰色的酒吧
settings in there?
设置在那里?
The gray bar, which is actually transparent and
灰色的酒吧，实际上是透明的
showing the all settings MVC behind it.
显示其背后的所有设置MVC。
Kinda, fuzzed out a little bit.
有点，有点模糊了。
That gray bar is drawn by the navigation controller.
那个灰色的栏是由导航控制器绘制的。
That and a toolbar on the bottom,
底部的工具栏，
which I'll talk about in a second, that's the only thing
我一会儿会讲到，这是唯一的东西吗
that the navigation controller actually draws in its view.
导航控制器实际上绘制了它的视图。
The rest of its view, it fills up with another MVC.
其余的视图，它充满了另一个MVC。
The view from another MVC,
来自另一个MVC的视图，
in this case the all settings MVC.
在这种情况下，所有的设置MVC。
The contents are all this "all settings MVC".
内容都是“所有设置MVC”。
Just like with the tab bar controller where there was
就像标签栏控制器一样
that tab bar item that had like the icon and
那个标签栏项目，像图标和
the title on it.
标题。
Same thing with the navigation controller.
导航控制器也是一样。
That word settings at the top,
顶部的单词设置，
the navigation controller MVC is getting that word by asking
导航控制器MVC通过询问得到这个词
the MVC that it's currently showing what's your title.
它现在显示的是你的标题。
It gets that from this var navigation item.
它从这个var导航项中得到。
It's a UI view control thing,
它是一个uiview控件，
just like tab bar item has all the tab bar things, navigation
就像标签栏项有所有标签栏一样，导航
has all the navigation, UI navigation things.
有所有的导航，UI导航。
So if you look at the API for navigation item,
如果你看一下导航项的API，
it has things in there like title, and I'm gonna show
它有类似标题的东西，我要展示
you another property that it's gonna use in a second to get
另一个属性，它马上就会用到
more information to draw.
画的更多信息。
If I click in this table view actually,
如果我点击这个表格视图，
if I click on general right there, then a new MVC is
如果我在这里点击“一般”，那么新的MVC就是
gonna slide in on top of that old settings one.
在旧的设置上滑动。
Now, the old settings one is completely non-visible but
现在，旧的设置是完全不可见的
it's still there.
它还在那里。
This is like a stack of cards,
这就像一堆卡片，
where I've put a new card on top.
我在上面放了一张新卡片。
The other card is no longer on screen, okay,
另一张牌不再在屏幕上，
you won't see it any more.
你不会再看到它了。
But it still exists in memory, in the navigation controller.
但它仍然存在于内存中，在导航控制器中。
So now we have three MVCs involved in this
现在我们有3个mvc
Navigation Controller, the Navigation Controllers' MVC,
导航控制器，导航控制器的MVC，
the all setting ones that is now in the back of this one,
所有的设置都是在这个后面，
and this one, the General Settings MVC.
这个，一般的设置MVC。
Now, by the way, there,
顺便说一下，
you can have toolbar buttons along the bottom here.
你可以在底部有工具栏按钮。
They look similar to the tab bar ones,
它们看起来和标签栏一样，
but they're a little different.
但它们有一点不同。
That is set with the toolbar item, the var in
这是用工具栏项设置的，var in
the General Settings MVC, not in the Navigation Controller.
一般的设置MVC，不在导航控制器中。
So as new MVCs slide in, the toolbar buttons at
因此，当新的mvc出现时，工具栏按钮就在
the bottom would change, because they're connected to
底部会改变，因为它们是相连的
whatever happens to be on top of the deck of cards.
不管发生在牌堆上面的是什么。
Notice also that there's a back button.
注意，还有一个后退按钮。
You see that back button?
看到那个后退按钮了吗?
It's called settings.
它被称为设置。
That button was automatically put there by navigation
这个按钮是通过导航自动放置的
controller.
控制器。
And if you click that,
如果你点击它，
it's gonna go back to the other card.
它会回到另一张牌上。
The all settings, so that's all done for you.
所有的设置，都为你完成了。
But if I click somewhere in here,
但是如果我点击这里，
like on Accessibility there, then it goes to another MVC.
就像在可访问的地方一样，它又转到另一个MVC。
Now we've seen four MVCs so far in this thing.
到目前为止，我们已经看到了4个mvc。
And if I click on Larger Text in here, I get yet
如果我点击这里的大字，我就会得到
another MVC..
另一个MVC . .
Now we have five MVCs.
现在我们有5个mvc。
So these MVCs just keep stacking on top, and
这些mvc只在顶部保持堆栈
each of the new one that comes on is its own world.
每一个新出现的都是它自己的世界。
It's completely on its own.
它完全是独立的。
And of course if we start pressing the back button up
当然，如果我们开始按下按钮
there on the left, it goes back to the previous one.
在左边，它回到上一个。
Notice the title of the back button is even set
注意back按钮的标题甚至设置
to be the title of the previous MVC so
成为前面的MVC的标题
you know what can happen when you click it.
你知道当你点击它的时候会发生什么。
And we can go all the way back to the all settings at
我们可以回到所有的设置
the very top.
最顶端。
Now there's no back button because
现在没有后退按钮了
there's no other cards.
没有其他的卡片。
So that's what navigation controller
这就是导航控制器
looks and works like.
看起来,像工作。
Okay, you guys have all seen this UI, I'm sure, in apps.
好吧，你们都看过这个UI，我敢肯定，在应用程序里。
Super common.
超级常见。
So let's talk a little bit of how the navigation controller
我们来谈谈导航控制器
works behind the scenes.
在幕后工作。
How how you make this thing work.
你怎么让这个东西起作用的。
So when do you need a navigation controller?
你什么时候需要导航控制器?
Well, let's see you have an MVC, right there, and
好吧，让我们看看你有一个MVC，在这里，还有
you got another whole pile of UI down here in the corner
角落里还有一大堆UI
that you wanna add, but just won't fit.
你想补充，但不适合。
You wanna be able to do the accessibility stuff and
你想要做可访问性的东西
the larger texts and all that we saw on the previous slide.
更大的文本和我们在之前的幻灯片中看到的。
But it obviously,
但很明显,
it's not gonna all fit in one phone screen so
它不会在一个手机屏幕上显示出来
you need more space.
你需要更多的空间。
So what you do is you create a new MVC that controls all that
所以你要做的是创建一个新的MVC来控制所有这些
UI that is completely independent of that.
完全独立于此的UI。
And it just knows how to manage that.
它只知道如何管理。
Now they might share a model, because maybe they're
现在他们可能共享一个模型，因为他们可能是
all looking in the settings database.
所有查看设置数据库。
That's fine.
这很好。
But they're not talking to each other in any way.
但他们并没有以任何方式交谈。
The only time they ever talk to each other,
他们唯一一次交谈，
is when it first comes on screen,
当它第一次出现在屏幕上时，
as you'll see in a moment.
你马上就会看到。
So I have two MVC's now,
现在我有两个MVC，
to control all the UI that I wanna present.
来控制我想要呈现的所有UI。
So let's use a NavigationController to make
让我们使用NavigationController来做
these come on screen.
这些出现在屏幕上。
And so here's a NavigationController,
这是一个导航控制器，
it's just MVC.
它只是MVC。
It doesn't really have a model that's okay but it has a view.
它并没有一个模型，但它有一个视图。
And inside that view there is a special var that's pointing
在这个视图里有一个特殊的var指向
to its view called RootViewController,
它的视图叫做RootViewController，
that's just points of to the controller of the MVC that's
这只是MVC控制器的一点
at the root it's the base card.
它的根是底牌。
The all settings one we saw on the previous page.
我们在前一页看到的所有设置。
So it just has this bar.
它只有这个条。
You just set that to something, and
你只要把它设置成某个东西，然后
now you'll have an MVC.
现在你会有一个MVC。
And as soon as you do that, as soon as you set that,
一旦你这么做了，
it's going to take that MVC's view and
它将采用MVC视图
put it in its view with that little gray bar.
把它放在那个灰色的小酒吧里。
And it's gonna ask it navigation item for
它会要求它的导航项
the title, and get the title.
标题，并获得标题。
Perfect example.
完美的例子。
This is super simple.
这是超级简单。
And then let's say you have a button inside this UI, or
然后假设你有一个按钮在这个UI中，或者
like a line in the table view, like get me more settings or
就像表格视图中的一行，比如给我设置更多设置
accessibility or whatever.
可访问性等等。
And you touch that.
和你联系。
Now, when you touch that, it's going to create one of these
现在，当你触摸它的时候，它会创建一个这样的
MVCs on the right, it creates it at that moment.
mvc在右边，它在那个时候创建它。
As soon as you touch it, it creates a new one.
一旦你触摸它，它就会创造一个新的。
Every single time you go to a new card,
每一次你去看一张新卡，
it creates a new one.
它创造了一个新的。
Not back, but every time you go forward to a new card,
不是回来，但每次你向前进一张新卡，
it always creates a new one.
它总是创建一个新的。
That's something I'm gonna say three or
这是我要说的三种
four times in this slide so
这张幻灯片上有四次
as to make sure you understand it.
为了确保你能理解它。
This activity of going to a new one is called segueing.
这种去新的活动叫做segue。
This particular segue's called a show or a push segue.
这个segue叫做show或push segue。
Which just means a segue in a navigation control with
这意味着导航控件中的一个segue
the stack of cards.
堆栈的卡片。
Now when you do that, you get the back button for
当你这样做的时候，你就得到了back按钮
free, it just automatically appears up there because
自由，它会自动出现在那里
that top bar like I say is
就像我说的那样
drawn by the navigation controller's part of its view.
由导航控制器的部分视图绘制。
And when you click that back button,
当你点击那个后退按钮，
of course what happens is interesting here.
当然，这里发生的事情很有趣。
Of course this slides back, but what happened to that MVC?
当然，这些幻灯片会回来，但是MVC发生了什么?
Gone.
一去不复返了。
Deallocated from the heap.
从堆中分配。
So when you go back,
所以当你回去的时候，
whatever card was on top gets thrown away.
上面的牌都被扔了。
So MVCs, as you're kind of getting the picture here,
所以mvc，正如你在这里看到的，
they're pretty ephemeral.
他们是非常短暂的。
MVCs don't really stick around for a long time.
mvc在很长一段时间内都不会真正坚持下去。
Now the root card on a Navigation Controller,
现在，导航控制器上的根卡，
it's gonna stick around pretty long,
它会粘在一起很长，
as long as that Navigation Controller is on screen.
只要那个导航控制器在屏幕上。
But mostly MVCs kind of come and go.
但大部分的mvc都是来来去去的。
And it's their models that tend to be persistent.
他们的模型往往是持久的。
When you create a new MVC,
当你创建一个新的MVC时，
you usually hook it up to a database or a network or
你通常把它连接到数据库或网络上
something, something persistent.
一些东西,一些有持久的东西。
And so that's why it's showing something new.
这就是为什么它展示了一些新的东西。
Or it's an MVC that showed something new every time.
或者它是一个每次都显示新事物的MVC。
So that's how a navigation controller works.
这就是导航控制器的工作原理。
I'm gonna talk a little bit how we hook all of this up.
我要稍微讲一下我们是怎么把这些联系起来的。
Because of course we're gonna do all this hooking up with
因为我们当然要勾搭上
control drag in Xcode, that's how we hook everything up.
control拖动到Xcode中，这就是我们把所有东西都连接起来的方式。
But I wanna talk a little bit about the code
但我想谈谈代码
behind so you know.
所以你知道后面。
There's an important var that is in these viewControllers,
在这些视图控制器中有一个重要的var，
like tab bar controller, and
和标签栏控制器一样
navigation controller, and split view controller.
导航控制器和分屏视图控制器。
It's called viewControllers, and
它被称为viewcontroller
it's an optional array of UIViewControllers.
这是一个可选的UIViewControllers数组。
And it means different things depending on
这取决于不同的东西
which one you're in.
哪一个你。
each tab, with the left most tab's MVC's at 0 and then 1,
每个标签，左边大部分的MVC在0，然后1，
2, 3, 4 is just the rest of the MVCs.
For a split view 0 is always the master, 1 is always
对于分屏视图0始终是主，1总是
the detail, and there's never any other ones in this array.
细节，在这个数组中没有其他的。
For a navigation control, 0 is the base card, and 1, 2, 3,
对于导航控件，0是底牌，1 2 3，
4, etc., are the ones stacked on top, in order.
So that's how you can kinda get at them.
这就是你如何去了解他们的方法。
Now, we don't usually, this is a bar, it can be set but
现在，我们通常不会，这是一个酒吧，它可以设置，但是
we usually don't set this bar, we don't set the things,
我们通常不设置这个栏，我们不设置这些，
we either use things that we do in our UI, which I'll show
我们可以在UI中使用它，我将展示它
you or even like in Navigation Controller, there's push and
你甚至喜欢导航控制器，有push和
pop methods to push MVCs on and pop them off of the stack.
使用pop方法将MVCs推到堆栈上并将其弹出。
Now, it's great to have this var ViewControllers, but
现在，有了这个var视图控制器很好，但是
how do you get the Split View Controller or
如何得到分屏视图控制器
get the Tab Bar Controller if you're in one?
如果你在一个标签栏控制器?
Okay if I'm the all settings MVC or
如果我是所有的设置MVC
I'm one of the health data ones that we saw on the tab
我是我们在标签上看到的健康数据之一
bar, how do I get the navigation controller I'm in,
bar，我怎么得到我所在的导航控制器，
or the split view I'm in or the tab bar I'm in?
或者是我所在的分屏视图?
Well all UIViewControllers have these three vars,
所有的UIViewControllers都有这三个vars，
tab bar controller, split view controller and
标签栏控制器，分屏视图控制器
navigation controller.
导航控制器。
And if you are in one of those things this will return
如果你在其中一件事上，这将会回来
the one you are in.
你在里面的那个。
And if you're not in one, it will return nil.
如果你不在一个，它会返回nil。
So that's how you find out
这就是你的发现
the Split View Controller you're in.
你在的分屏视图控制器。
And you can use the combination of
你可以结合使用
For example, if you're the Master in a Split View,
例如，如果你是分屏视图的主人，
these two things.
这两个东西。
you can find your detail MVC by saying
你可以通过说，找到你的详细MVC
what's the split view controller I'm in?
我在的分视图控制器是什么?
Get its View Controllers, look at View Controller sub 1
获取它的视图控制器，查看视图控制器sub 1
because that's always the detail.
因为那总是细节。
So I just clicked and went up and over and got it.
所以我只是点击了一下，然后往上走，然后得到了它。
You see?
你看到了什么?
And I use the question mark, the optional chaining there
我用问号，这个可选的链接
because I might not be in a split view controller.
因为我可能不在分屏视图控制器中。
And then it obviously will return nil for
然后它显然会返回nil
my detail, which is fine cuz it would be nil if I'm not in
我的细节，很好因为如果我不在，它将是零
a split view controller obviously there's no detail.
分屏视图控制器显然没有细节。
Now, how do we wire all this stuff up?
现在，我们怎么把这些东西连接起来呢?
Of course we're gonna do it all graphically.
当然我们要用图形来表示。
Let's start by at looking at the split view and
让我们从拆分视图开始
how we do this.
我们该怎么做。
Now to create a new view controller, whether it's one
现在创建一个新的视图控制器，不管它是1
of these view controllers of view controllers that we
这些视图控制器的视图控制器
were talking about or just a regular view controller.
或者只是一个常规的视图控制器。
You go down to the object pallet and you drag it out
向下到对象托盘，然后拖出来
into your storyboard just like a button, except you're just
进入你的故事板，就像一个按钮，只是你只是
dragging to open space and it's created there.
拖动到开放空间，它在那里创建。
Now when you drag a split view controller out, it's
现在当你拖拽一个分屏视图控制器时，它是
actually gonna drag out kind of empty, detail and master.
实际上会拖出一个空的，细节的和主人的。
You never want that.
你永远不希望这样。
I don't know why it really does that.
我不知道为什么会这样。
Just delete those.
仅仅删除这些。
You're obviously gonna have your MVC's like your
很明显，你的MVC就像你的
calculator and your graphing view controller sitting in
计算器和你的绘图视图控制器
your storyboard and you're gonna drag the split view
你的故事板会拖拽分屏视图
controller and you're gonna wire it up to those.
控制器，你要把它连接起来。
So you're gonna delete any of the extra junk that comes out.
所以你要删除掉出来的多余的垃圾。
Then you just Ctrl+drag like we do,
然后按Ctrl +拖动，
our favorite gesture in a face builder, is Ctrl+drag.
我们在face builder中最喜欢的手势是Ctrl +拖动。
We just Ctrl+drag from the split view controller
我们按Ctrl +拖动从分屏视图控制器
to the master and to the detail, so I'll get up.
对于大师和细节，我将站起来。
So this is what that looks like.
这就是它的样子。
Here I've got split view controller on the left.
左边是分屏视图控制器。
I've got calculator view control on the top and
上面有计算器视图控件
I've got a graph and control view on the bottom.
我在底部有一个图和控制视图。
So I'm just gonna control,
所以我要控制，
drag from the split view controllers,
从分屏视图控制器中拖拽，
the calculator controller.
计算器控制器。
This little black window is gonna come up.
这个小黑窗将会出现。
I'm gonna choose master view controller from the list and
我将从列表中选择master视图控制器
that's gonna hook that one up top to my master.
这将把它和我的主人联系起来。
Then, I'm gonna Ctrl+drag to the bottom one, the black
然后Ctrl +拖动到下一个，黑色
window comes up I'm gonna choose Detail View Controller
窗口出现，我会选择Detail视图控制器
then it's gonna make that connection.
然后它会连接。
Okay, as simple as that.
就这么简单。
Now you've got the split view with master that's
现在你已经有了主的分屏视图
calculator of your controller and
你的控制器的计算器
detail that is going to be a graphic view controller.
这将是一个图形视图控制器。
Now, one interesting thing here though,
现在，有一件有趣的事，
is this split view does not work on an iPhone.
这种拆分视图在iPhone上不起作用。
Well it works on iPhone plus, iPhone six plus or
它适用于iPhone +，iPhone 6 plus
seven plus, the kind of big ones, but it does not work on
7 plus，大的，但它没有作用
a normal iPhone, it's just not enough screen real estate to
一个普通的iPhone，只是没有足够的屏幕空间
really do the split view thing, so we can't do it.
做分屏视图，我们不能这么做。
So, what we really want to do is build a UI though that
所以，我们真正想做的是建立一个UI
works on all the devices.
在所有的设备上工作。
So to do that, what we do is we're gonna wrap
要做到这一点，我们要做的就是包装
the master and the detail if we want.
如果我们想要的话，master和detail。
We're gonna wrap them in a navigation controller.
我们要把它们包在导航控制器里。
And then when they're on iPhone,
当他们在iPhone上的时候，
they won't use the split view part,
他们不会使用分屏视图，
they'll just use the navigation controller.
他们会使用导航控制器。
It's really cool, how it figures this out.
它很酷，它是怎么计算出来的。
The way to wrap a view controller that's in there,
包装一个视图控制器的方法，
you wanna wrap it in a Navigation Controller,
你想把它包裹在导航控制器里，
you just go to the Editor menu,
你只要去编辑器菜单，
the same place we did embed and stack view,
我们做嵌入和堆栈视图的地方，
and some of that.
和一些。
And you select the whole scene of your MVC, and
然后选择MVC的整个场景
you go to the Editor Menu and
你去编辑菜单
you say embed in navigation controller.
你说嵌入导航控制器。
So I've selected that top, calculate and control and
所以我选择了顶部，计算和控制
when I do that,
当我这样做,
it's going to put it inside a navigation controller.
它会把它放到导航控制器中。
Did you see that?
你看到了吗?
Now, I've got the flip view, it points to a navigation
现在，我有了flip视图，它指向一个导航
controller, so the master of this flip view is actually
控制器，所以这个视图的主人实际上
that navigation controller, and then the navigation
导航控制器，然后是导航
controller root view controller is the calculator.
控制器根视图控制器是计算器。
So, if you're on a device that can do split view,
如果你在一个可以分屏视图的设备上，
like an iPad or a plus,
比如iPad或plus，
you're going to get the whole split view effect.
你会得到整个拆分视图效果。
But if you're on just an iPhone,
但如果你只使用iPhone，
it's not going to do the split view.
它不会执行分屏视图。
It's just going to do the navigation controller.
它会做导航控制器。
So, when you look at the detail,
所以，当你看细节的时候，
it's going to slide it in.
它会把它放进去。
Whereas if you're on a iPad in landscape,
而如果你在iPad上，
you're gonna see Master and Detail at the same time.
你会同时看到Master和Detail。
Now, you can also do the same thing- yeah, and so
现在，你也可以做同样的事情——是的，所以
the UINavigationController is the Master,
UINavigationController是Master，
as, as I talked about.
就像我说的。
So you can do the same thing with the Detail.
你可以对细节做同样的事情。
Now why would you ever do that with the Detail?
你为什么要这样做呢?
Because yo've already done it with the master and
因为你已经和大师做过了
so you gotta click in the master to get to the detail,
所以你要点击master来得到细节，
so yo're kinda already gonna be in a navigation controller,
所以你已经在导航控制器中了，
and tha's true.
,那是事实。
But wha's kinda nice about putting the detail
但wha对细节的描述很好
in a navigation controller is you get that little title bar,
在导航控制器中，你得到那个小标题栏，
you know the little gray title bar?
你知道那个灰色的小标题吧?
So now, your master and
现在，你的主人和
your detail both have a title bar on the top and
你的细节都有标题栏在上面
they match up nicely.
他们很好地匹配。
So if you wanna title on your detail,
如果你想要详细说明，
that's a good thing to do.
这是件好事。
The only thing to be careful there though is
唯一要注意的是
now your detail in not a graph view controller.
现在你的细节不是图形视图控制器。
Your detail is now a navigation controller.
你的detail现在是一个导航控制器。
So if you wanna get the graph view controller and
如果你想要得到图形视图控制器
like talk to it, tell it what to graph or
就像跟它说话一样，告诉它要画什么
something like that, you need to get the root view
像这样，你需要得到根视图
controller of the navigation controller.
导航控制器的控制器。
So it's just subtle difference but
所以这只是细微的差别
if you wrap your detail in a navigation controller,
如果你把你的细节包装在导航控制器中，
the detail has come become a navigation controller.
细节已经成为导航控制器。
It's easy to get to the graph view controller,
很容易得到图形视图控制器，
cuz the root view controller of the navigation controller.
cuz导航控制器的根视图控制器。
That's how you wire up the split views so
这就是分割视图的方式
that it works cross platform, all devices.
它可以跨平台，所有设备。
The last thing we're gonna talk about is segueing.
最后我们要讲的是segue。
So we know how to wire up the split view controller, and
我们知道如何将分屏视图控制器连接起来
we know how to do a navigation control,
我们知道怎么做导航控制，
we just embed it in the navigation controller.
我们将它嵌入到导航控制器中。
I didn't talk about the tab bar controller by the way,
我之前没有讲过标签栏控制器，
but that's easy.
但这很简单。
You just drag a tab bar controller out and CTRL + drag
你只需拖动标签栏控制器并按CTRL +拖动
to all of the MVC's that you want it to show,
对于所有的MVC来说，
and you can actually even drag the little icons around
你甚至可以拖动小图标
to put them in order.
把它们按顺序排列。
You can even set the icons in text in the interface builder
您甚至可以在接口构建器中设置文本中的图标
with an inspector.
检查员。
So, tab bars, so simple I don't even want to waste time
所以，标签栏，很简单，我甚至不想浪费时间
showing it, but so we know how to kind of hook up and control
展示它，但我们知道如何建立和控制
drags and wire up, or embed to do the navigation controllers.
拖动和连接，或嵌入到导航控制器。
How do we go from one to the other, like in the navigation
我们如何从一个到另一个，就像在导航中一样
controller, how do we go from all settings to settings and
控制器，我们怎么从所有的设置到设置和
from settings to accessibility,
从设置可访问性,
and accessibility to larger text?
更大的文本的可访问性?
How do we set up that transition or how do we make
我们如何建立这种转变呢
it so that we press a button in our calculator split view
因此，我们在计算器拆分视图中按下一个按钮
and it causes that graph to be replaced with a new graph?
它会导致图像被新的图形取代吗?
How do we do that?
怎么做呢?
We do that with what are called segues.
我们用segue来做这个。
I've alluded to this earlier.
我之前提到过。
These are the kinds of segues that exist.
这些是存在的segue。
There's a show segue.
有一个显示segue。
That means, if you're in a Navigation Controller,
这意味着，如果你在导航控制器中，
slide a card on.
幻灯片一张卡片。
There's Show Detail,
有显示的细节,
which if you're a Navigation Controller,
如果你是导航控制器，
still means slide a card on.
仍然意味着一张卡片。
But if you're inside a Split View,
但如果你在分屏视图里，
it means put this new MVC where the detail goes.
它的意思是把这个新的MVC放在一个细节上。
That's why it's called Show Detail.
这就是为什么它被称为显示细节。
So Show Detail behaves differently depending on
因此，显示细节的行为取决于不同
whether you're in the Split View or
不管你是在分屏视图还是
whether you're in a Navigation Controller.
不管你是在导航控制器里。
Modal segue, it's kind of interesting one.
Modal segue，很有趣。
It takes over the entire screen and lets
它占据了整个屏幕
the MVC that you're segueing into own the whole screen.
你segue到的MVC拥有整个屏幕。
Now, these can be somewhat disturbing to the users cuz,
这些可能会让用户感到不安，
I can't get back to where I was,
我无法回到原来的位置，
cuz there's no back button or anything.
因为没有后退按钮什么的。
That whatever MVC comes up and
不管MVC是什么
takes over the screen has to provide some UI to get out of
接管屏幕必须提供一些UI来摆脱
there like cancel or done, or something.
好像取消了，或者做了什么。
So we try to stay away from Modal if we can.
所以如果可以的话，我们尽量远离模态。
So Popover is sort of the same as Modal, but
弹窗和模态是一样的
instead of taking over the whole screen, it just puts up
而不是接管整个屏幕，它只是简单地说
a little pop-up window, a little popover window,
一个弹出窗口，一个弹出窗口，
you've seen that, on iPad especially.
你已经看到了，尤其是在iPad上。
It's still Modal, because if you click anywhere else,
它仍然是模态的，因为如果你点击其他地方，
the popover goes away.
弹出窗口消失。
So it's essentially modal.
这是基本模态。
It's a little nicer than modal, though,
它比模态的好一点，
because you can really see the background kinda grayed out.
因为你可以看到背景变灰了。
And if you don't want what's in the popover,
如果你不想要弹出窗口，
just click somewhere else and it goes away.
只要点击其他地方，它就消失了。
So yeah, popover's a little nicer than modal.
弹窗比模态更漂亮一点。
But it only works on fairly large screens,
但它只在大屏幕上运行，
unless you have a really small pop over window.
除非你有一个非常小的弹出窗口。
Now, I'm going to emphasize for
现在，我要强调一下
the second time what I said before segues always create
第二次是我在segue之前说的
a new instance of the MVC.
MVC的一个新实例。
All of the segues, all of them, modal, popover, show,
所有的segues，都是，modal,popover,show，
slide in the min,
下滑的最小值,
show detail, even show detail in the split view.
显示细节，甚至在拆分视图中显示细节。
If you have a calculator and you say graph my function and
如果你有一个计算器，你可以把它写出来
you segue to a graph view controller,
你segue到一个图形视图控制器，
it throws away the one that was there and
它扔掉了那个在那里的
puts a new one there, always creating new MVCs.
在那里放一个新的，总是创建新的mvc。
So think of these MVCs as ephemeral, they come alive,
因此，把这些mvc看作是短暂的，它们会活过来，
they do their job and they go away.
他们做自己的工作，然后离开。
They don't live you know, long lives.
他们不活在你的生命里。
Now the master and a split view.
现在，主和分屏视图。
The root view of a navigational,
导航的根视图，
they tend to live fairly long.
他们往往活得很长。
But even those, if that split view, if that navigational
但即使是那些，如果那是分裂的观点，如果这是导航的话
were to go off screen, they go away as well.
如果要离开屏幕，他们也会离开。
So how do we make these segues happen?
那么我们如何让这些segue发生呢?
Of course, we use control drag.
当然，我们使用control拖动。
We love to use control drag, so here for
我们喜欢使用control拖动，所以这里
example is the calculator example.
示例是计算器示例。
I've got a split view.
我有一个分屏视图。
And in my calculator there in the upper right
我的计算器在右上角
I have a button it's very hard to see but
我有一个按钮，很难看到，但是
it's a little picture of a graph.
这是一张图的小图片。
So that's the button that when I press it,
这是按钮，当我按下它时，
it's gonna take whatever's in my calculator and graph it.
它会取计算器里的任何东西并画出来。
So if I've typed in for example m cosine,
如果我输入了m cos，
it's gonna draw a cosine wave, that's what that button does.
它会画一个余弦波，这就是这个按钮的作用。
So I just go into interface builder here, control drag
我在这里输入接口生成器，control拖动
from that button down to the detail right there.
从这个按钮到细节。
When I let go,
当我放手,
it's going to put up just a little black window,
它只需要一个小的黑色窗口，
which I'll show you a little detail of.
我会给你们看一些细节。
It looks like that.
像这样。
And I'm gonna pick the segue I want.
我将选择我想要的segue。
Well, since this is a Split view, if I can,
因为这是分屏视图，如果可以，
I'm going to show detail.
我将展示细节。
Put it on the right side of the split view.
把它放在分屏视图的右边。
Now, if I were in this same storyboard, but
现在，如果我在这个故事板中，但是
I was on an iPhone non-plus,
我在iPhone上没有，
then even though I'm picking show detail here,
尽管我在这里选取了一些细节，
it's still going to do the navigation controller show,
它还是要做导航控制器show，
because there is no split view side, when I'm on the iPhone.
因为在iPhone上没有分割视图。
So I pick the segue type I want, and
我选择segue类型，以及
it creates the segue.
它创造了segue。
And it appears in your storyboard,
它出现在你的故事板中，
it can even be clicked on and inspected.
它甚至可以被点击和检查。
And in fact you're gonna always want to click on
实际上你总是想要点击
that thing and inspect it.
那件事，检查一下。
Cuz you don't wanna set this thing right here which
因为你不想把这个放在这里
is the identifier.
是一个标识符。
Every segue has an identifier, it's just the string and
每个segue都有一个标识符，它只是一个字符串
that identifier is what's you're gonna use in your code
这个标识符是你在代码中将要使用的
to talk about this segue.
来讨论这个segue。
And I'll talk about what you've
我来谈谈你的经历
been talk about regarding segues, any moment here.
关于segue，任何时刻都在讨论。
So always set that.
所以总是设置。
And you wanna set it,
你想要设置它，
the identifier to be something that kind of says what is
标识符表示什么是什么
segue does.
segue。
So in this case it shows a graph, so
在这个例子中，它显示了一个图
I call this show graph.
我把它叫做show graph。
That's how you set up your segue.
这就是设置segue的方式。
And that's true for navigation controller as well.
导航控制器也是这样。
If you have a navigation controller and
如果你有一个导航控制器
you have a button that causes another card to slide on you
你有一个按钮可以让另一张卡在你身上滑动
just control drag from that button to the other MVC.
只需要从那个按钮control拖动到另一个MVC。
And then you use a show segue, and it'll just work.
然后你使用一个show segue，它只会工作。
Has to be all inside,
必须全在里面，
embedded in navigation controller, of course.
当然，嵌入在导航控制器中。
So what can you do with these identifiers?
那么如何处理这些标识符呢?
It is actually possible to cause a segue to happen from
实际上可能会导致一个segue的发生
code, with performSegue withIdentifier, but
用performSegue withIdentifier，但
I'm not gonna talk about that, cuz we're never gonna do that.
我不想谈这个，因为我们永远不会那样做。
We always gonna have buttons,
我们总会有按钮，
well I'm not gonna say we're never gonna do that,
我不会说我们不会那样做，
but we won't be doing that in your assignment three,
但在你们的作业中，我们不会这样做，
that's for sure.
这是肯定的。
It's pretty rare.
很罕见。
But you can do it with performSegue.
但你可以用performSegue。
But the more important use of the identifier is not causing
但是更重要的使用标识符并没有引起
segues to happen cuz segues kinda happen
要发生类似的事情
automatically when the buttons are pressed.
按下按钮时自动。
It's to prepare for a segue.
它是为segue做准备。
This is the most important method in all of
这是最重要的方法
multiple MVC programming is this preparing for segue
多MVC编程是为segue做准备的
method which I'm gonna show you in a moment here, okay.
我一会儿要给你们看的方法，好的。
And remember, we're all segueing to a new MVC
记住，我们都在segue到一个新的MVC
freshly created, so it's always raw.
新创建的，所以它总是原始的。
So we have to prepare it to do what it's going to do.
所以我们必须做好准备，去做它将要做的事情。
Here is the method.
这里是方法。
It's called prepare for segue, and
它叫做prepareforsegue，和
it also has a sender argument right there.
它也有一个sender参数。
The segue that's passed along that first argument
第一个参数传递的segue
is just a little container that contains interesting
只是一个包含有趣的小容器
information about the segue.
关于segue的信息。
For example, the identifier, Show Graph.
例如，标识符，Show Graph。
And very importantly, the controller that you're seguing
非常重要的是，你所segue的控制器
too, because the whole point is here,
因为整个点在这里，
you're suppose to be preparing this MVC that's going to
你应该准备这个MVC
come on screen.
出现在屏幕上。
To do its job so
做它的工作
you get that thing from this little segue object.
从这个小segue对象中得到这个。
The sender is kinda like buttons,
发送者有点像按钮，
the button sender when we had the action there.
当我们有动作的时候，按钮发送器。
It's just what object is instigating this.
这就是这个问题的原因。
So in the calculator example you're gonna have a button
在计算器的例子中，你会有一个按钮
clicking causing this segue, it's gonna be that button.
点击造成这个segue，它将是那个按钮。
Okay, the button that's causing the segue.
这个按钮导致segue。
But it's Any because anything, when we saw the example
但这是任何原因，当我们看到这个例子的时候
of the all settings, we were clicking on table view cells
在所有设置中，我们点击了表视图单元格
there not buttons but cells in what's called a table view,
这里不是按钮，而是表格视图中的单元格，
which we're gonna talk about week after next.
我们下周接着讲。
And so that could be the sender.
这就是sender。
Or you might have done perform segue on the previous slide,
或者你可能在上一张幻灯片上做了执行segue，
that actually let you set the sender so
这样你就可以设置sender了
you've tell it anything you want, it could be nil also.
你告诉它你想要什么，它也可以是nil。
We don't use it that much.
我们不用那么多。
The first thing I'm
我的第一件事
do is going to be get the identifier.
将会得到标识符。
Note that it can be nil so
注意它可以是nil
I'm gonna say if let to get it out of that segue right there.
我想说，如果我们把它从那个segue中取出来。
And I need that identifier cuz I need to know which segue I'm
我需要这个标识符因为我需要知道我是哪个segue
doing because I might have three buttons
因为我有三个按钮
on my calculator that segued to three different things.
在我的计算器上，segue到三个不同的东西。
Now you're not gonna have in assignment three but you could
你不会在作业3，但你可以
have multiple buttons segueing to different things.
有多个按钮来segue到不同的东西。
So you need to know which segue you're talking about.
所以你需要知道你说的是哪个segue。
So you switch on it and then you check the case.
你打开它，然后检查这个箱子。
And in the case of Show Graph,
在Show Graph的例子中，
which is the one we're gonna do right here,
这就是我们要做的，
we're going to prepare that graphing MVC to do its job.
我们要准备这个图形MVC来完成它的工作。
Now, in order to talk to that graphing MVC,
现在，为了和这个图形MVC，
we have to get it as a graph controller.
我们必须把它作为一个图形控制器。
Now the type of that destination view controller
目标视图控制器的类型
that's in the segue object is just UIViewController,
这在segue对象中就是UIViewController，
it doesn't know that it's a graph view controller or
它不知道它是图形视图控制器
something like that it's just UIViewController.
它只是UIViewController。
So we have to use as,
所以我们要用as，
remember the "as?" I told you you could cast anything.
还记得”?“我告诉过你，你可以投任何东西。”
Not just any object, you can cast a UIViewController to try
不只是任何对象，你可以cast一个UIViewController来尝试
and down cast it to a specific view controller.
然后把它丢给一个特定的视图控制器。
So here I'm going to try and cast the destination view
这里我将尝试转换目标视图
controller to be a graph controller.
控制器是图形控制器。
I'm gonna assume the graph controller is the type of
我假设图形控制器是
the controller of my graph MVC.
我的图形MVC的控制器。
And if I'm able to do that, which I should be,
如果我能做到这一点，
because I know this is the show graph segue, so
因为我知道这是show graph segue
I better be, if,
我最好,如果,
if I'm not then probably I wanna raise an exception here.
如果我不是，我可能想在这里提出一个例外。
Because I'm really expecting to be able to do it.
因为我真的希望能做到。
Maybe I use as exclamation point right there instead of
也许我用的是感叹号，而不是
as question mark as it'd be bad if I was doing this and
作为问号，如果我这样做会很糟糕
it wasn't actually graphcontroller.
实际上这不是graphcontroller。
But anyway, I get the graphcontroller so
总之，我得到了graphcontroller
now VC, this variable VC is of type graphcontroller, so
现在VC，这个变量VC是图形控制器，所以
I can start setting vars in it,
我可以开始设置vars，
calling methods, whatever I need to do to prepare that
调用方法，无论我需要做什么准备
graph controller to do its job.
图形控制器完成它的工作。
Now in the Calculator case,
在计算器中，
what I'm doing is I'm going to somehow have to
我要做的是，我要怎么做
set the model of the graph you control or
设置您所控制的图形的模型
something to show the graph I want.
这是我想要的图形。
Based on what 's in my calculator.
根据计算器里的东西。
So, I'm preparing it to do what it does.
所以，我准备做它所做的事情。
I'm pretty much never going to talk to this thing again.
我再也不会跟这个人说话了。
So I'm gonna give it all the information it needs to do to
所以我要给它所有需要做的信息
go to a job.
去工作。
This is kind of one time set up and
这是一段时间
that's the way MVCs need to work through, object oriented.
这是MVCs需要工作的方式，面向对象。
They get set up once and then they just live on their own,
他们建立了一次，然后他们自己生活，
they do their own job.
他们做自己的工作。
They don't talk back to the person who brought them up or
他们不会和抚养他们的人顶嘴
to anyone else.
别人。
They live on their own.
他们靠自己生活。
So you can do anything you want to here, to try to do it.
所以你可以做任何你想做的事情，试着去做。
One thing to warn you here though and
这里有一件事要提醒你
half of you will trip over this.
一半的人会因此而绊倒。
When you're doing this preparation
当你做这个准备的时候
of that graph controller,
图形控制器,
that graph controller's outlets have not been set.
该图形控制器的outlet尚未设置。
I told you that IOS hooks up those outlets to really really
我告诉过你，IOS会把这些媒体连接起来
quickly, but this is one case where it doesn't quite hook
很快，但这是一个不完全挂钩的情况
them up fast enough.
他们不够快。
When you're doing vc.property1 = whatever,
当你做风投。property1 =,
vc.callMethodToSetItUp, at that time,
vc。callMethodToSetItUp,当时,
none of vc's outlets are set.
vc的outlet都没有设置。
So you can't do anything in the UI.
你不能在UI中做任何事情。
So if you're collecting information for what to,
如果你正在收集信息，
to do in the UI,
在UI中做，
you're gonna have to store it in some vars or something.
你必须把它储存在一些vars或其他东西里。
And then later, either in the did set
之后，在did集合中
of those outlet centers, or I'm gonna teach you about view
在这些出口中心，或者我要教你们的观点
controller life cycle next week.
控制器生命周期下周。
There's other methods that happen later,
之后还有其他的方法，
that you can be sure that the outlets are set.
你可以确定outlet已经设置好了。
So this is in red, any time I put something with red inside,
这是红色的，任何时候我把红色的东西放到里面，
you really wanna pay attention.
你真的想要集中注意力。
So the outlets are not set in graph control or
所以outlet不是在图控件中设置的
when you're preparing, the process of preparing.
当你准备的时候，准备的过程。
You can also prevent a segue from happening,
你也可以防止segue发生，
let's say if the calculator and you try to hit graph and
假设计算器，试着打图
you're on the middle of a binary operation,
你正在进行二进制运算，
pending binary operation.
等待二元运算。
Well you can't graph that.
你不能画出来。
There's no way to graph a pending binary operation.
没有办法绘制一个挂起的二进制操作。
Three times, what's the graph of three times?
三次，三次的图形是多少?
It's nothing.
没什么。
So, you wanna prevent it.
所以，你想要阻止它。
So, in your assignment three you're gonna wanna use this
在你的作业中，你会用到这个
method and be able to control a shared perform segue,
方法和能够控制一个共享的执行segue，
you're gonna return false.
你会返回false。
When you're in the middle of a pending operation, okay?
当你处于等待操作的中间时，明白吗?
And so that's it for today.
这就是今天的内容。
There's no Friday section this week.
这周没有星期五的课。
Next Friday section is going to be on performance analysis
下周五节将介绍性能分析
cuz there's going to be an extra credit item
因为将会有一个额外的信用项目
in assignment three that does that.
在作业3中，这样做。
You'll see that when it goes out.
当它熄灭时，你会看到它。
Next week I'm gonna do
下周我要做
a demo about all this multiple MVC stuff.
一个关于所有这些MVC的演示。
I'm gonna start talking about the View Controller Lifecycle.
我将开始讲视图控制器生命周期。
And then the super important topic, Protocols and
然后是非常重要的话题，协议和
Delegation.
代表团。
UI things like scroll views and table views.
UI类似于滚动视图和表视图。
We'll start that next week cuz all you're learning up till
我们下周开始，因为你一直在学习
now is kinda the basics.
现在是最基本的。
Swift and views and multiple MVCs.
Swift、视图和多个mvc。
One you got that basics in now you can start doing these
现在你可以开始做这些了
more powerful objects.
更强大的对象。
Now, assignment three is already on the class forums.
现在，作业3已经在课堂论坛上了。
You can start it right now.
你现在就可以开始。
It's got really two major points to it.
它有两个要点。
One is a custom UI view that does graphing.
一个是定制的uiview，它会绘图。
A truly a custom MVC that does graphing.
一个真正的自定义MVC，可以绘制图形。
And that thing is completely independent of your
这是完全独立于你的
calculator.
计算器。
In fact I would recommend you create a new app
事实上，我建议你创建一个新的应用程序
to create that MVC.
MVC的创建。
Because if you don't wanna be polluted by you calculator,
因为如果你不想被计算器污染，
it's just a generic graphing MVC.
它只是一个通用的图形MVC。
Once you've got that,
一旦你明白了,
you're gonna combine it with your calculator
你要把它和计算器结合起来
like I'm talking about here,
就像我说的，
where you're going to click a button, and
你要在哪里点击一个按钮
it's going to graph what's in your calculator.
它会在你的计算器里画出什么。
So you can get started on that today because you already
你们今天就可以开始了，因为你们已经开始了
know everything you need to know about UI view and
了解关于UI视图的所有知识
doing a custom draw method.
做一个自定义绘制方法。
So you could start drawing your graph and
所以你可以开始画你的图
building that custom graphing view.
构建自定义图形视图。
You could even build the custom MVC because you're
您甚至可以构建自定义MVC，因为您是
building it as a single MVC to start.
将其构建为单个MVC开始。
But you're gonna wanna wait til Monday to try and
但你要等到周一再试
hook it up to your calculator because you're
把它和计算器联系起来，因为你是
gonna wanna see me do the demo of a split view and
想看我演示分屏视图
all that stuff and see that happening.
所有这些都发生了。
It'll help you when you start hooking your two
当你开始胡来的时候，它会帮助你的
MVC's the graphing one and the calculator one together.
MVC的图形和计算器一个在一起。
And because you need next Monday
因为你需要下周一
this assignment's not gonna be due until the next Monday.
这个作业要到下星期一才交。
Okay, so you got a nice 10 or 11 days to get it done.
好吧，你有10到11天的时间来完成它。
But I strongly recommend you use the next few days to go
但我强烈建议你在接下来的几天里去
ahead and get started on the view part of it.
在前面的视图部分开始。
Because that's more than half of the assignment and
因为这超过了作业的一半
you can make a big head start into it.
你可以让一个大脑袋开始。
The last thing is the last reading assignment
最后一件事是最后一次阅读作业
also went out today.
今天还出去。
The due date is pretty much next Wednesday.
下个星期三就会有截止日期了。
But that is going to make it so
但这将使它成为现实
you've read the entire Swift document.
你已经阅读了整个Swift文件。
So by the end of this assignment,
所以在这个作业的最后，
you should feel like you know everything that's in there.
你应该觉得你知道里面的一切。
Now of course, I don't expect you to know every
当然，我不希望你知道每一个
single detail about every single thing.
每件事都有一个细节。
But I expect you
但我希望你
if you like want to do a nested function I expect you
如果你想要做一个嵌套函数，我想要你
to be able to know where to go look to find that out.
能够知道去哪里寻找答案。
Or you wanna do optional chaining and
或者你想做可选的链接
you can't quite remember you know where to go look it up.
你不记得你知道去哪里查查看。
That's a reference document.
这是一个参考文档。
So you wanna know what's in there.
你想知道里面有什么。
Even if you don't memorize at all.
即使你根本不记得。
That's it.
就是这样。
See you next time.
下次再见。
>> For more, please visit us at stanford.edu.
>> 更多课程详见 stanford.edu